[MUSIC]
［音乐］
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
Okay, well, welcome to lecture 7 of CS193P.
欢迎来到 CS193P 课程的第七课
This is the winter of 2015.
这是2015年冬季的课程
And today,
今天
we are going to talk about multiple MVCs, all right?
我们想讲一下多重 MVC（Multiple MVCs）的内容
That includes split view controller,
这将涉及到 Split View Controller 和
navigation controller.
Navigation Controller
We talked about tab bar controller a little bit
我们在上一讲中已经讲过一点 Tab Bar Controller 的内容
last time.
We're also gonna talk about segues which is how we make
我们同样会在本节课中讲到 Segues
all those multiple MVCs kind of transition to each other.
Segues 是多重 MVC 之间转换的一个东西
And I have a big demo that shows it all off.
这里我会有一个比较大的 Demo 来演示这部分
And that after that demo I'll come back.
在 Demo 之后，我们回到主题
We'll talk about popovers which are similar thing for
然后，我们会谈到 Popovers，Popovers 和多重 MVC 有一些相似的地方
having multiple MVCs but are not quite the same.
但不是完全一样的
So that's why I've kind of
所以这是为什么我把 Popovers 这块
segregated them off to the end.
放到最后的原因
And we'll have a demo about that.
同样我们在这里有一个 Demo
All right. So MVCs working together.
好了，介绍完毕。多重 MVC 一起协同工作
These are the slide we saw at the end of last time.
这些是我们上次课最后看到的 Slide
We're trying to build apps by taking our MVCs and combining
我们尝试通过让我们的 MVC 和
them with tab bar, split view, and navigation controller.
Tab Bar, Split View, Navigation Controller 混合在一起来构建我们的应用
We talked about tab bar controller which is
我们讲过 Tab Bar Controller 就是
just simply four or five or however many
用一个小的 Tab Bar 来讲将四、五个或者任何数目的
MVCs all connected by just having this little tab bar so
MVC 连接在一起，然后让你选择你想要展示那一个
the bottom just picks which MVC you want to see.
MVC 的一个东西
Each MVC by the way in the tab bar's completely independent.
在 Tab Bar 中的任意一个 MVC 都是独立的
It runs on its own.
独立运行
It doesn't depend on the other ones.
不依赖 Tab Bar 中的其他 MVC 而运行
It actually might be kind of bad object on your
所以，假如你应用中，Tab Bar 中的 MVC
programming really for them to depend on the other one.
是依赖于其他的 MVC 的话，这是一种不好的编程方式
So, tab bars for peers that aren't really talking to each
所以 Tab Bar 是为了那些层次上互相有关系的 MVC 而设计的
other they're just working together, they're related.
并不是为了那些在逻辑上协同工作的 MVC 而设计的
Maybe they share a model and
可能它们共用同样一个 Model
they're each having a different part of the model
也有可能它们用同一个 Model 中的不同部分
or whatever.
或者其他情况
And then we talked about split view controller,
接下来我们讲到 Split View Controller
which only has two MVCs in it, a master, and a detail.
它其中只有两个 MVC，一个 Master，一个 Detail
We call them master and detail, by the way,
我们称之这两者为 Master 和 Detail 是因为
because the master is usually the one determining what's in
Master 决定了 Detail 的内容是什么
the detail.
So the master is letting you view something,
举例来说，Master 让你浏览一些东西
and then you're going to use the detail to see more detail
然后 Detail 让你浏览你在 Master 中做的东西更加详细的信息
about what you're doing in the master, okay?
明白了吗？
So that's why we call it master and detail.
这就是我们为什么叫它们  Master 和 Detail
So we're going to pick up now with navigation controller.
接下来，我们讲一下 Navigation Controller
So navigation controller is just yet another MVC whose
Navigation Controller 就是一个 MVC
view is multiple of other MVCs and navigation controller can
它的 view 由其他的 MVC 组成
handle any number of other MVCs.
Navigation Controller 可以包含任意数量的 MVC
Okay.
And it puts them on screen, it shares the screen instead of
它把其他的 MVC 放在屏幕上，与其他类型的 Controller 不同的是，它共享这个屏幕
just putting them side by side or putting them with the tabs,
而不是将其他的 MVC 一一放置，或者放在 Tab Bar 上
it puts them like a stack of cards.
它像一堆卡片一样放置这些 MVC，这里我们把 MVC 类比成卡片
Okay?
明白了吗？
So NavigationController's basically stacking them
所以，Navigation Controller 基本上就是像一堆卡片一样放置 MVC
like cards and you can only see the one on top.
所以，你只能看到最上面的那个 MVC
That's how NavigationController
这就是 Navigation Controller 如何
shares the small screen space between multiple MVCs.
在多重 MVC 之间共享一个小的屏幕空间的
So it's gonna stack these MVCs up.
它会将这些 MVC 堆起来
So here's a NavigationController.
这里有一个 Navigation Controller
And it's got an MVC in it.
它的里面有一个 MVC
This is the All Settings MVC from your device.
这里它显示的 MVC 是你设备的 All Settings MVC
If you go look in your iPhone or
当你打开你的 iPhone
whatever, you'll see the settings app looks like this.
或者其他 iOS 设备时，你会看到设置的应用程序样子就是这样
So this is just an MVC that's kind of the top level.
这就是在最顶层的 MVC
Has all the settings accessible from here.
它包含了所有设置的一个入口
Now the navigation controller is drawing only a little part
需要注意的是，由 Navigation Controller 绘图的一小部分
of it's view here, which is that title bar.
是 Title Bar（顶部的一块区域）
And the navigational controller will put the title
Navigation Controller 会在 Title Bar 这里显示标题（Title）
there, and also you can have a couple of buttons up at
当然你还可以在这里放置一些按钮
the top and the navigational controller draws that part.
同样 Navigation Controller 会帮你绘制
The rest of it is totally drawn,
而在它之外的部分
and even underneath that title bar, totally drawn by
甚至是在 Title Bar 底下（而不是下方）的那部分
whatever MVC is on top of this stack of cards.
由 MVC 堆栈顶部的那个 MVC 来负责绘图
Okay, and right now the only thing on
在这个图片中
our stack of cards is this All Settings MVC.
我们 MVC 堆栈顶部的那个 MVC 是 All Settings MVC
Now even though the contents of
尽管顶部的部分由 Navigation Controller 来绘制
the top are drawn by the navigation controller, what
但是，顶部部分的内容
the contents are is determined by the MVC that's showing.
仍是由当前 MVC 堆栈顶部的 MVC 所决定的
Okay? And that's done with this
UIViewController property called navigationItem.
UIViewController 里有一个叫 navigationItem 的属性
So if you go look in the documentation for
如果你查看 UIViewController 的文档时
UIViewController you'll see this property navigationItem.
你会看到有 navigationItem 这么一个属性
If you click through to the type UINavigation item you'll
如果你查看 UINavigation 类型的东西的文档时
see that it's got a lot of properties and
你看到它有许多的属性
they're like left button, right button, title.
例如左按钮、右按钮、标题
Things like that. So,
等等类似的东西
the way the navigation controllers figures out
Navigation Controlller 通过查询哪个 MVC 是当前 MVC 堆栈顶部的 MVC
what to put in the top bar is it asks whatever MVC is on
来决定它在 Title Bar 上布局的方式
top of the stack.
So as you go to different MVCs being on this stack of
所以栈顶 MVC 在不断变化的同时
cards that thing at the top will change.
Navigation Controlller 顶部区域也会随之变化
Okay?
有问题吗？
So, let's say I click on General here,
这里我说，我点击 General
because I want to see general settings.
因为我想看看通用设置
Okay, so I click on it, and a new MVC gets put on top of
好的，当我点击 General 的时候，一个新的 MVC 就放在 MVC 堆栈的顶部了
the stack of cards, so now I can't see the other one, okay?
现在，我就看不到其他的 MVC 了
This new one is overlaying it,
新出现的 MVC 覆盖在其他 MVC 之上了
and this is just a general settings MVC.
这里是一个 General Settings MVC
Completely different MVC,
一个完全不同的 MVC
completely independent of the other one working on its own.
完全独立于其他 MVC 而工作的一个 MVC
By the way,
这里顺便提一句
I don't have a good screenshot of this unfortunately, but
这里我不巧，没有一个很棒的截图来给你们展示其他的功能
it's also possible for the navigation controller to
但是 Navigation Controlller 可以
draw some buttons along the bottom there.
在底部绘制几个新的按钮
A little small sliver on the bottom.
可以在底部有一个小的灰色栏
And it get those button items to put there,
然后将按钮至于那里
by asking the MVC that's on top of the stack of cards for
而这个灰色栏的按钮布局是可以通过堆栈顶部的 MVC 的
the toolbar items property.
toolbarItems 属性来设置的
So if you look at toolbar items,
当你查看 toolbarItems 的文档时
it's just an Array of these bar buttons, so
你会发现它就是一系列 bar buttons 组成的数组
any MVC that returns anything in that Array,
当任意一个在 Navigation Controller 堆栈中的 MVC
when it's in a navigation controller like this,
在 toolbarItems 数组中返回什么东西的时候
those buttons will appear at the bottom.
这些按钮会出现在屏幕的底部
So those would change each time you go
同样，每次当你在堆栈上添加新的 MVC 的时候
to the next thing on the stack as well.
这些按钮也会随之变化
So let's go ahead and click on something here.
现在让我们继续点击什么东西
Let's click on, oh sorry, the back button.
让我们点击，噢，返回按钮
Yeah, you see there's a back button in the upper left.
你可以在屏幕的左上方看到一个返回按钮
The back button says, Throw the top card off.
这个返回按钮的意思是，移走最顶部的那张卡片
That's basically what back means.
这是返回最基本的意思
Throw the top card on
移走 MVC 堆栈中最顶部的那张卡片
this stack of MVCs that we're building, throw it off, and
then I'm going to go back to where I was before.
然后将我返回到我之前的那个位置
So that's how back works, it just throws it off.
这就是返回如何工作的，扔掉卡片
And when it throws it off, it completely throws it off,
当从MVC 堆栈中最顶部的那张卡片时，它是完全被移除的
it disappears.
它消失了
Completely gone.
完全消失
All right?
明白了吗？
Out of the heep, okay?
从堆栈中完全移除了
All right, so let's put another card on the stacks,
好的，接下来让我们在堆栈中增加一个卡片
I'm going to click on accessibility here,
我点击这里的 Accessibility
another card's going to slide in,
另外一个卡片将会移入
I'm trying to simulate the animation of it but in keynote
我尝试在 Keynote 里模仿这个动画
I can't exactly do it, but it slides in from the side.
我不能很精确地模仿它，但是他从侧边移进去
And this is yet
现在，这是另外
another completely different MVC, the accessibility MVC.
另外的一个完全不同的 MVC，Accessibility MVC
And we can pick something out of here,
这里我可以选择一些东西
like I'm going to pick larger text right there, and
比如，我想让字体变大一点
another MVC is going to slide in.
这时，会有另外的一个 MVC 移入
So we have four MVCs, totally different MVCs,
现在，我们在卡片堆栈上有4个完全不同的 MVC 了
on our stack of cards right here.
And the one on top, which is the last one that I chose,
最顶上的那个，也就是我最后选择的那个
this larger text MVC, is showing.
正在显示的，Larger Text MVC
Okay? The rest of them are there,
明白了吗？在它的底下有其他的 MVC
you just can't see
但你看不见
them because they're underneath this top card.
因为被顶部的卡片覆盖住了
Okay, so now let's do the back button.
好的，现在让我们做返回操作
So I'm going to click this back button in the upper left
我将点击左上角的返回按钮
and when I do, it takes that larger text one off, throws it
当我点击的时候，它会将 Larger Text MVC 移走
out, and now we've got the accessibility card, which is
从堆栈里扔掉，现在我们有 Accessibility 的卡片了
now the top of our stack which only has three things on it.
Accessibility 的卡片变成了堆栈上三个卡片中最顶端的那个
And we can do back again.
我们继续返回
It goes back to the general one.
现在返回到了 General 卡片
We do back again.
再返回
It goes back to the very top.
回到了最最上层
Of course, once we get back to the very top there's no
当然，当我们回到了最最上层的时候
more back button because this is the only card on the stack.
不会再有返回按钮了，因为那是堆栈上唯一的卡片了
Okay, so everyone understand what
现在，每个人对 Navigation Controller
a NavigationController is?
都理解了吗？
It's just a stack of MVCs.
简单的说，就是 MVC 堆栈
All right?
没问题吧？
But it's just like split view controller and
但是它和 Split View Controller 和
UITabBar Controller in that it is showing multiple MVCs.
UITabBarControlller 一样，它们的功能都是展示多重 MVC
So I'm going talk a little bit about how navigation
所以我将更详细地讨论一下 Navigation Controller
controller works internally, so you can get a feel for it.
内部的工作方式，让你们有一个更直观的感受
And I'm going to try to mix it with our MVC image that we
同时，我会尝试将它和我们其他的 MVC 混合在一起
had so you can kind of combine the two concepts in your mind.
这样你就能在你的大脑里混合这两种概念了
So, let's say I had an MVC.
这里，我说，我有一个 MVC
This one up here, the purple MVC thing.
顶上的那个紫色的 MVC
And I had more features I wanted to put on there, but
我本想在这个 MVC 之上添加一些其他的功能，但是
there's just not enough room on the screen anymore,
屏幕的空间不够
I've kind of maxed out.
我已经尽量使用了所有可用的屏幕空间
Or it's just those features don't logically make sense to
或者从逻辑上，我要添加的功能不应当
be in the same place.
显示在这个 MVC 之上时
Well, what I would do is create another MVC to manage
我应该怎么做呢？我应该创建另外一个 MVC
those other features that won't fit,okay?
去管理那些不属于这个 MVC 的那些功能，对吗？
And, so now though I need a way to have those two MVCs
所以，我应该找到某种方法，让这两个 MVC
share the screen and I can use a split view controller or
能够共享一个屏幕空间。这里，我能使用一个 Split View Controller
tab bar controller if they were peers or
或者 Tab Bar Controller，如果这两者之间是平等的关系
I could use navigation controller.
当然我也可以使用 Navigation Controller
So, let's see what it would look like to
让我们来看看
use a navigation controller to have these two MVCs which
当我们使用一个 Navigation Controller 来结合这两个 MVC
they're related share the screen.
使得它们共享同一屏幕空间的情况
So a navigation controller is just an MVC, okay?
还记得 Navigation Controller 也是一个 MVC 吗？
It's a controller of an MVC.
一个 MVC 的控制器（Controller）
And it's view is a little rectangular area that usually
它的视图是一个小的
fills the entire screen or a portion of the screen.
通常是布满整个屏幕空间，或是屏幕空间的一部分的矩形区域
It's got the title.
它有一个标题
But it's a special MVC and they've just got an outlet
但是它是一个特殊的 MVC，它有一个叫做 rootViewController 的 outlet
called Root View Controller that points to an MVC.
这个 outlet 指向某个 MVC
[UUU] points to the controller of an MVC.
确切的说，是指向某个 MVC 的控制器
And when it is pointing to that, then the navigation
当这个 outlet 指向某个 MVC 的控制器时
controller puts that MVC's view, okay, its view property.
Navigation Controller 便会将那个 MVC 的视图绘制出来，也就是 view 属性
All right, we know that UIViewController has
我们已经知道 UIViewController 有一个
this very important property called view,
非常重要的属性，叫做 view
which is its top level of its view.
它是所有视图中最顶层的那个
It puts that on the screen underneath this title thing.
Navigation Controller 把它放置在屏幕上，标题栏之下
So it fills the entire rectangular area and
因为它会布满整个矩形空间
then the title kind of overlaps it transparently,
所以在标题栏会变成半透明，以显示标题栏之下的那部分
semi-lucent transparency.
毛玻璃透明效果
Okay?
明白了吗？
So that's great.
很好
So we got it in there.
我们现在成功把一个 MVC 和 Navigation Controller 结合在一起了
Now how do we get the other MVC on?
我们如何让其他的 MVC 和 Navigation Controller 继续结合在一起？
Well, when a ui element inside the view of
好的，当某个在这个视图中的 UI 元素
this MVC like a button or something like that
例如一个按钮或者其他的东西
is pressed then it can cause another MVC to get created.
被按下的时候，这能导致其他的 MVC 被创建
You notice that MVC just appeared?
你注意到这个 MVC 刚出现了吗？
It wasn't there before.
之前这个新的 MVC 没有出现过
But as soon as the button gets pressed in this guy's view,
但是，在用户的视图中，只要有按钮一按下
this MVC's view, that thing gets created.
那么一个新的 MVC 就会被创建
And that's something important to notice that we're always
在这个过程中，需要注意到的是
going to be creating a new MVC when we do these transitions.
当我们做这些转换时，我们始终会创建一个新的 MVC
Okay? Transitioning to a new card.
明白了吗？转换到一个新的卡片
In a split view,
在一个 Split View 中
we do something in the master that changes the detail.
我们在 Master 中做的操作会改变 Detail
That's always creating a new,
这也就是说，它始终创建了一个新的 Detail
even the first time we press a tab bar, but
这种情况甚至存在于，当我们按下了 Tab Bar
only the first time for the tab bar, it creates a new MVC.
而且也是 Tab Bar 第一次被用户按下的时候
Okay? So it creates this new MVC.
明白了吗？所以这样的操作会创建一个新的 MVC
And then the NavigationController just
接着，Navigation Controller 就会移动到
moves over to put that MVC's view on top.
新创建的 MVC 之上
All right?
And then of course you've got the back button.
当然，之后你就会在左上角有一个返回按钮
When you click the back button,
当你按下返回按钮的时候
it goes back to the first MVC.
Navigation Controller 回到了第一个 MVC
And look what happens to that MVC.
让我们来看看新创建的 MVC，它会发生什么
Gone.
消失了
Okay.
That is not hidden or something.
它不是被隐藏起来了
It's just gone.
它消失了
It got de-allocated probably from the heap.
它从内存空间中被 deallocated 了
Okay? And then we're back to here.
我们回到了第一个 MVC
Okay, so that's how navigation controller works.
好的，这就是 Navigation Controller 工作的方式
Very simple.
非常的简单
And, you know, split view and
你要知道，Split View 和
tab bar are similar kind of mechanism.
Tab Bar 的工作方式也是类似
Okay. So
好的
how do we get at these sub-MVCs?
另外一个问题，我们如何能够取得这些子 MVC 呢？
So let's say I had a split view controller or
假设说，我有一个 Split View Controller
a navigation controller or a tab bar controller.
或者一个 Navigation Controller 或是一个 Tab Bar Controller
How do I get at the things on the stack of cards,
我如何去获取这些卡片堆栈上的东西呢？
or the two things the master and detail?
或者说，我如何去获取 Master 和 Detail 中的东西呢？
And the answer is
答案是
they all have a property called view controllers.
它们都会有一个叫 viewControllers 的属性
And it's an Array of view controller.
它是由 UIViewController 组成的一个数组
Okay?
明白了吗？
And that it's all the view controllers in a system.
它里面存储的是一个系统中所有的 ViewController
So in a split view, there will be only two in there,
在 Split View 中，这里面只会有两个元素
the master and the detail, in the tab bar there will be how
Master 和 Detail，在 Tab Bar 中
ever many tabs there are, in a navigation controller there
这里面会有 Tab 数目个元素，而在 Navigation Controller 中
will be however many cards are on the stack.
这里面会有堆栈上卡片数目个元素
That's how many things will be in that Array.
这就是知道这个数组有多少个元素的方式
And it's settable too which is a little weird,
当然它是可以被设值的，但是这么做有点点奇怪
we don't usually set things but you can do it.
通常我们不会对它直接设值，但是不代表不可以这么做
And the way we usually set it is we're going to
我们通常对它设值的方式是
do it in the story boards or navigation controller for
比如我们在 Storyboard 的 Navigation Controller 中
example has methods like push and pop view controller that
有 push 和 pop view controller 的方法
will push view controller onto the stack.
这样的操作会在这个数组中 push view controller
But that is doing that in code and
但是这是在代码中设值的方式
we are usually doing all of this stuff in story boards.
通常我们在 Storyboard 中做这一系列的操作
So that's how you get at the sub things of
以上就是如何你获得这些子 MVC
these three kinds of view controllers.
这些 view controller 的方法
What about, how do I get a hold of the view controller?
那么，我如何获得一个 view controller 呢？
Okay? How do I get that
我如何获得一个
navigation controller?
Navigation Controller
How do I get a pointer to it, or whatever?
我怎么获得它的一个指针呢？
Well it turns out every view controller knows if it's
答案是，每个 view controller 都知道
inside a navigation controller or if it's inside a split-view
它自己是不是身处在一个 Navigation Controller 或者是 Split View
controller, or if it's inside a tab bar controller.
Controller 或者是 Tab Bar Controller 中
It knows.
它自身知道
And so UI view controller has these three properties: tab
因为，UIViewController 有三个属性：
bar controller, split view controller,
tabBarController，splitViewController
navigation controller.
和 navigtionController
And they will return to you the split view
splitViewController 属性会返回给你
controller that the view controller is in.
它处在哪个 Split View Controller 中，其他的属性类推
Okay?
明白了吗？
If it's in one, if it's not then it returns nil.
如果它不在某个 Controller 中，这个属性返回的是 nil
And notice some view controllers might be inside a
注意到某些 view controller 会在一个 Navigation Controller 中
navigation controller, inside a split view controller.
而这个 Navigation Controller 又嵌套在一个 Split View Controller 中
So more than one of these things can be
所以这些属性可以超过一个
non-nil at a time.
同时不为 nil
Because we can nest these things to build more powerful
我们可以利用这些嵌套来构建一个
user interfaces.
强大的用户界面
So let's just use the example, if I'm the master in
让我们举个例子，如果我是一个 Split View 中的 Master
a split view, and I want to get the detail.
我想获取 Detail
Well I can get the split view controller I'm in by
这里我可以通过访问 splitViewController
saying split view controller.
来获得我在哪个 Split View Controller 的指针
I'll put the little question mark there,
这里我会输入一个问号
that's optional chaining.
因为 Optional Chaining
If it's nil,
如果它返回的是 nil 的话
then I'm obviously not going to get my detail.
那么显然我不应该获得 Detail（因为我根本不在一个 Split View Controller 中）
And then I'm going to say view controller sub 1,
然后我输入 viewControllers[1]
because we know that view controller sub 1 in
因为我们知道，viewControllers[1] 在
split controller is the detail.
Split View Controller 中代表的是 Detail
So now I've got the detail and
现在，我就获得了 Detail
I can talk to it I could, you know, get to my detail.
我就能向 Detail 发送消息了
So presumably I might want to tell it to
假设这里，我希望告诉 Detail
do things display things or whatever, okay?
显示某些东西或者做其他的事情
So that's how we get at these things in code if we need to,
所以，如果我们需要的话，我们可以通过这样的代码来获取我们想要的指针
but we often don't need to because we can manage most of
但我们并不常需要，因为我们能够
this in the story board.
在 Storyboard 完成大部分的操作
And so how do we wire this up, how do we create this
所以，我们如何在 Storyboard 里链接起来这些 MVC
relationship between these split through tab bar and
如何在在子 MVC 和 Split View Controller，Tab Bar Controller
navigation controller and these all the sub-MVCs.
Navigation Controller 之间建立关系呢？
And it can be done in code, okay?
这些都可以通过代码来完成
But we're gonna do it
但是我们在这节课上
in storyboards in this class all the time.
将通过 Storyboard 来完成
Okay. And we're just
我们要做的就是
gonna use Ctrl + drag to do it.
Control + 拖动来链接多重 MVC
So let's see what that looks like.
让我们来看看这是什么样子的
I'll do it for split view controller,
以 Split View Controller 举例
we're just going to go the utilities area,
我们找到 Utilities 区域
the same place we drag out a button or something like that.
和我们之间找到按钮和其他的 UI 元素同样的地方
We're going to drag out a split view controller.
我们拖出来一个 Split View Controller
Now, when it comes out,
当它被拖动出来的时候
it's going to come out with a whole bunch of other MVCs
它会带出来一整连串的 MVC
pre-attached to it in attempt to help you, but
这些 MVC 已经链接在一起以方便你的使用
usually you're just going to delete those so
但通常你会删除它们以链接你自己的 MVC
that all you have left is the split view controller itself.
所以你只需要保留的就是 Split View Controller 本身
Okay?
明白了吗？
And then you're going to Ctrl+Drag from the split view
然后，你从 Split View Controller 开始
controller to the master and
按住 Control 键拖动，链接 Split View Controller 和 Master
Ctrl+Drag from the split view controller to the detail.
同样方法，链接 Split View Controller 和 Detail
And that's how you are going to do the wire.
这样你就链接起来了 Master 和 Detail
So this is what it looks like.
这就是链接过程看上去的样子
Here I have a storyboard.
这里我有一个 Storyboard
I've dragged out of split view controller.
我从 Split View Controller 开始拖动
That's that gray thing on the left.
Split View Controller 也就是左边灰色的那一个
Okay?
没问题吧？
I deleted all the things it was attached to so
我删除了之前附属在 Split View Controller 的东西
I just had that.
所以我只保留了 Split View Controller 本身
Then I Ctrl+Drag to,
然后我按住 Control 键并拖动
in this case my master, which is my calculator.
在这个例子中，我的 Master 是我的计算器
When I do that, it's going to put up this little thing says
当我做这个操作的时候，这里会提示说
okay, what kind of connection do you want to make?
“你想要创建什么样类型的链接？”
And you're going to pick master view controller there.
选择 Master View Controller
And that's going to make like a little connection to it.
这样就建立了一个链接
And then I'm going to Ctrl+Drag down to my detail,
然后，我按住 Control 键并拖动到 Detail 上
which is going to be the right side of my split view.
这样 Detail 就会成为我 Split View 中右侧的部分了
And here I'm going to choose I want Detailed View Controller.
这里同样会弹出一个提示，选择 Detailed View Controller
Okay?
明白了吗？
And then I'm going to have this,
然后我就拥有了一个
fully hooked up split view.
完整的 Split View
And that's it.
这就是如何通过 Storyboard 链接 Split View Controller 的方式
So it's very easy to hook these things up.
非常简单就可以链接起来
All right, and tab bar,
好的，Tab Bar Controller
you can hook up exactly the same way.
你可以通过几乎相同的方法把子 MVC 链接起来
Connect as many of them as you want, okay?
想链接多少 MVC 都可以
Navigation controllers can be done a little bit differently,
Navigation Controller 有一点点的不同
which we'll see in a second, okay?
稍后我们可以看到
But there's a problem here which is that a split view
但是这里有一个问题，那就是
can't display side by side on an iPhone.
Split View 不能在 iPhone 上显示
Or at least not anything but an iPhone 6 plus.
更确切的说，不能在 iPhone 6 Plus 以外的 iPhone 型号上显示
That's the only one big enough to really display side
因为 iPhone 6 Plus 是唯一一个拥有足够大小
by side.
来显示 Master 和 Detail 的型号
So a split view really can't work on an iPhone.
所以 Split View 不算是真正能够使用在 iPhone 上的
Okay?
明白了吗？
The way we handle this is that iOS adapts its
我们处理这个方式是
user interface to whatever device it happens to be on,
因为 iOS 会在不同屏幕大小的设备上改变其用户界面
depending on how its size class is.
这依赖于其 Size Class 是什么
We'll talk about size classes later, but if it's compact,
我们稍后会讲到 Size Class，但如果想要兼容不同设备的话
like a phone, then it can't show it in a split view.
比如 iPhone，那么它没办法在 Split View 中显示
So how can I show it then?
我如何显示它呢？
If I have it master in a detail and
如果我有 Master 和 Detail
I wanna show it on an iPhone the way I show it is with
而且我想在 iPhone 上显示它的话
a navigation controller.
那么请使用 Navigation Controller
So instead of having master and
来替代同时在屏幕上显示 Master 和 Detail
detail on the screen at the same time on an iPad,
只有 iPad 可以同时显示
on the phone when I click in the master, same button that I
在 iPhone 上，我点击 Master 中同样的按钮
clicked to make the detail show it in split view,
用以在 Split View 中显示 Detail 的按钮
but when I click in the master on the iPhone is going to
同样的操作会导致 Detail 卡片滑入
slide the detail on as a card.
On the deck.
在层面上
All right.
On the navigation charts stack.
在 Navigation Controller 的堆栈上
Now the thing is though we want to
现在我们想要做的是
build one storyboard that will work for
让同样的一个 Storyboard 文件在不同的
both platforms and automatically adapts.
平台上适应其屏幕大小
So how do we do that?
我们应该如何实现呢？
We're just going to wrap our master in
我们要做的就是，将我们的 Master 嵌入
a navigation controller.
在一个 Navigation Controller 中
So here is a Navigation Controller,
这样，这里有一个 Navigation Controller
which is my master, it's the calculator, right?
它就是我的 Split View Controller 中的 Master，也就是我的计算器，对吗？
And you can see it's hooked up to the split view already, and
你能看到，它已经链接到 Split View 了
I'm just gonna select it, and then I'm gonna go to
这里我选择它，找到
the Editor menu and pick Embed in Navigation Controller.
Xcode 菜单中的 Editor，然后选择 Embed in Navigation Controller
See that embed?
看到那个 Embed in 了吗？
And this is what's gonna happen.
这就是我们要做的
Okay, the Navigation Controller,
好的，Navigation Controller
is going to the interposed between the split view and
将会在 Split View 和 Master 中充当一个中间者
the master.
So now the master, is in a Navigation Controller.
现在 Master 已经嵌入一个 Navigation Controller 中了
Now if I am on an iPhone, and I click in something
当我在 iPhone 上运行的时候，当我点击什么东西
that would change the detail, then it's going to push it
即将改变 Detail 的内容的时候，它会 push 这个
on that Navigation Controller, on top of the stack.
到 Navigation Controller 的堆栈顶上
But if I am on an iPad it's going to
当我在 iPad 上运行的时候
show them side by side.
它就会在右侧展示这个 Detail
So this structure that you see right here,
你这里看到的就是这个结构
split view, navigation control for
用 Split View，Navigation Controller
the master and then detail is very common.
这种结构来链接 Master 和 Detail 是十分普遍的
A universal way of specifying your UI so
这就是一个定义用户界面的方法
it works on both, okay?
而且这种方法是通用的（iPhone，iPad）
Now we can also put the detail inside of
这里，我们同样可以将 Detail 嵌入一个 Navigation Controller 中
a Navigational Controller too, why would we want to do that?
不过我们会问，为什么我们会想要这么做？
Well the only reason we would wanna do that,
唯一这么做的理由是
is cuz maybe we want
可能我们需要
the Navigation Controller's feature of a title, right?
Navigation Controller 的标题栏的功能，对吗？
Or little buttons we wanna put at the top.
或者是我们想在标题栏上放置一些按钮的功能
It's really nice for that.
这么做是个好方法
But, we don't need
但是，我们并不需要
a Navigation Controller down there for navigation,
用一个 Navigation Controller 来做导航
because we are never navigating from the detail.
因为我们从来不需要在 Detail 里导航
We only navigate to the detail.
我们只会导航至 Detail
So, it doesn't, itself, need to be in its own
它自身不需要一个 Navigation Controller
Navigation Controller, and we'll see that in the demo.
稍后我们会在 Demo 中看到
All right, so that's how we wire these things up.
好的，这就是我们如何链接这些东西的
Okay, and they end up looking like that.
它们最后应该会是这个样子的
Now how do we make these things appear?
接下来，我们如何将它们显示出来？
How do we make changes in our master,
我们在 Master 中做了一些改变
that cause something to appear in the detail.
如何能导致 Detail 去显示 Master 中的这些改变
Or if we have a Navigational Controller that has multiple
或者说，我们有一个 Navigation Controller
cards, when we clicked all those buttons and another card
它拥有许多卡片（MVC），当我们点击这些按钮的时候
kept coming on in the stack, how did we do that, okay?
另外的卡片会 push 进入堆栈，我们如何做到呢？
And the answer is we use segues, okay?
答案是，我们利用 Segues，明白吗？
So segues is, how these things transition from
Segues 是如何从一个 view controller 转换到
view controller to view controller.
另一个 view controller 的方式
There's really four kinds of segues.
iOS 里已经定义了四种不同的 Segues
There are custom segues, too, but
当然你还可以自定义 Segues
we're not gonna talk about that in this class,
但是本节课我们不会讨论到
kind of advanced, you almost never need those.
这些高级的 Segue，而且基本上你也不会用到
So there's four basic segues.
所以，有四种基本的 Segues
There's show segue, okay?
Show Segue
Which basically shows the MVC that you're talking about, and
简而言之，就是展示你正在交互的那个 MVC
if you're a Navigation Controller, it will show it
假如你是一个 Navigation Controller，它会将那个 MVC
on the, it'll put it on top of the stack of cards.
放置于堆栈之上并显示它
If you're not in a Navigation Controller,
假如你不是一个 Navigation Controller
then it will show it modally.
那么它会 Modally 展示这个 MVC
Okay, so now, modal presentation of an MVC,
下一个是 Modal 展示一个 MVC
we haven't talked about that with all these other things,
我们目前还没有在其他的地方讲到过
but basically it just takes over the entire screen.
但是，基本上它就是会布满整个屏幕空间
Okay? Just completely takes over the
只是将你想要展示的 MVC
entire screen, puts the MVC that you wanna show on screen.
完全布满整个屏幕空间
So it's very kind of disruptive to
可能对于用户，这会有一点点混乱
the user a little bit, because their app is stuck,
因为他们的 App 卡住了
it can only do what this MVC is asking them to do.
只有当这个 MVC 要求用户做一些操作的时候，这种方式才推荐使用
So I kind of recommend against using modal, and
我不太推荐使用 Modal
trying to keep your apps from doing that.
尽量不要在你的 App 中用到它
So if you're using a show segue,
所以当你使用一个 Show Segue 的时候
you probably wanna be in a navigation controller, so
你大概想在 Navigation Controller 中使用到
that it will slide it on deck.
因为这样的话会有一个滑入的效果
Because, then the user can always go back,
而且，用户使用可以返回
if they didn't mean that, they can go back.
用户假如误操作返回的话，还可以再回去
Then there is show detail segue, very similar to show,
接下来的是 Show Detail Segue，和 Show Segue 非常相似
the only difference with show detail is that if
唯一的区别就是，Show Detail Segue
you happen to be in a split view controller it
在 Split View Controller 中的效果就是
will show this MVC as the detail, okay?
在 Detail 中显示这个 MVC，明白了吗？
Otherwise if you are in Navigation Controller, but
否则，如果你在一个 Navigation Controller 中
not in a split view controller it just pushes it
而不是在 Split View Controller 中，这个效果就是
on the stack just like show would, okay?
在堆栈上 push 这个 MVC，滑入的效果，明白了吗？
So, show detail tiny difference there.
所以，和 Show 只有一点点的区别
It's just about split view.
只和 Split View 相关
So, it really helps you when you're in a split view
所以，如果你在使用 Split View 的时候，这个 Segues 确实很有帮助
decide whether what you want is the master to,
帮助你决定，你想要 Master 是什么
if the master is in a Navigation Controller,
如果 Master 嵌入 Navigation Controller 的话
if you want that to slide on the master?
如果你想要在 Master 上滑入？
The thing you're segueing to or
你 Segue 的目标 view controller
do you want it to appear in the detail, okay?
你是否想要它在 Detail 中显示
Then there's modal which forces this full
这里的 Modal 强制
screen takeover type of thing.
整个屏幕被 MVC 接管
I'm not even gonna talk about that, I'll talk about it
我不打算讨论到它
later in the quarter, but I don't wanna talk about it
我会在学期后部分讲一下，但是我不想过早涉及到
early because it can be used as a crutch to build UIs.
因为它可以作为构建 UI 的一个支撑
You really wanna be using Navigation Controllers, and
你肯定会用到 Navigation Controller 和
split view controllers to do that.
Split View Controller 来这么做的
And then a popover segue.
接着，Popover Segue
Now a popover segue pops the view controller that you're
Popover Segue 弹出 Segue 的目标 view controller
segueing to, up into a little window that's on top of
并让这个 view controller 显示在所有其他东西之上
everything else, but just a little window instead of
但是并不布满整个屏幕
taking over the whole screen.
它是一个小的窗口
But it, really is taking over the whole screen,
但是，实质上它是布满整个屏幕的
because the user an only interact with what's in
因为用户只能与这个 Popover 窗口（Window）进行交互
the little popover window, if they click anywhere else,
如果用户点击了除窗口以外的其他区域
it dismisses the popover window.
这就会取消这个 Popover 窗口
But what makes popover nicer than just modal is that,
Popover Segue 比 Modal 好的地方是
since it doesn't take over the whole screen, you can still
尽管它并不布满整个屏幕
kind of see grayed out where you came from, and if you
但是你可以让窗口背后的用户界面变灰变暗（grayed out）
click where you came from, it puts the popover away.
当你点击这些变灰变暗的区域，窗口会被弹走
So the popover has very easy to cancel, it's very easy for
所以 Popover 很容易取消
you just to get back to
很容易让用户回到
where they were if they didn't really mean to click that.
他们之前的界面，如果他们无意中点击到了的话
Okay, so that's popovers.
这就是 Popover Segues
So we'll talk over popovers at the end.
我们会在最后再讲到 Popover
Again I wanna emphasize what she was talking about on
再一次，我想强调的是
the previous slide segues of all kinds,
我们在上一页 Slide 中讲到的各种 Segues
no matter what you're doing, show detail, modal or popover.
无论你在干什么，Show Detail，Modal 或者 Popover
They always create a new MVC.
他们都会创建一个新的 MVC
You're never segueing to an existing MVC anywhere.
你从来不会 Segue 到一个已经存在的 MVC
You're always creating a new one always,
我们总是创建一个新的
that's what segues do.
这就是 segue 所做的事
Okay, that takes a little bit of
这需要你慢慢去
getting used to in your mind.
习惯这个概念
Because of course you see this stack of cards.
因为当你看到 stack 中的 View 的时候
Navigation one, and you press back.
跳转到一个，然后你点击返回
And then you click to go back to where you were.
然后你再点击进入到刚刚的界面
And you think you're going back to the same one.
你会认为你回到了原来的那个界面
But you're not. Because as soon as
但事实并不是这样的。因为当
that thing comes off the stack, [SOUND] it's gone.
这个 View 从 stack 中退出时，呼，它就消失了
Even in split view.
即便在 split view 中也是这样的
You click in the master it updates your detail.
点击 master 界面上的东西，你的 detail 界面就会更新
You click again in the master to update the detail,
你再次点击 master 界面的东西来更新 detail
and the detail changes and you think oh,
然后 detail 改变了，然后你会想，噢
that was the same thing it just got changed.
这和刚刚是一样的东西，只是改变了一点东西
No the previous one got thrown away and
不是这样的，先前的那个被丢掉了
new detail got created, okay?
你看到的是新的 detail 界面
So segues always created a new MVC.
因此 segues 总是创建新的 MVC
All right, so how do we make these segues happen, okay?
好的，我们怎么用这些 segue 呢
You can do this in code as well, and
你可以用代码来实现
I'm gonna show briefly how you do this in code.
我也会简单给你们展示一下怎么用代码实现
But in 90% of the time you're gonna do it
但是百分之九十的情况你都将会用
in a storyboard with control drag,
storyboard 中的 control 加拖动来实现
which is how we create most of the things we do in IOS.
这也是我们在 iOS 中创建东西的最常用的方法
So here's an example of doing it with the control drag,
这里是用 control 加拖动来实现 segue 的例子
I'm control dragging from a button in my calculator, so
我按住 control 然后从按钮拖动到我的 calculator
I added a button.
那么我添加了一个按钮
The icon is very, very small but
它的图标很小很小
it actually looks like a little graph.
但是事实上它看起来像一个小图表
So I'm control dragging from that in the upper right corner
那么我 control 拖动，从右上角
there down to the detail, because I
拖到 detail 这个界面
want when that buttons pressed I want the detail to be
因为我想当我点击了这个按钮，detail 界面就能够
replaced with a new graphing MVC, okay?
被替换为一个图标 MVC
When I let go it that,
当我放开鼠标
it's gonna say, what kind of segue do you want?
Xcode 就会问你想要哪一种 segue
This little black box is gonna appear.
将会弹出这个小小的黑色框框
And here I'm gonna pick Show Detail,
这里我会选择 Show Detail
because if I'm in a split view,
因为这是个 split view
I wanted to replace the detail.
我想要替代 detail
If I was in a Navigation Controller only,
如果这是个 Navigation Controller
I probably still would choose Show Detail because that
我也许仍然会选择 Show Detail 因为
also pushes on the stack.
这也会把 View 推入 stack 内
But if I were the master in a split view and
但是如果是 split view 中的 master
I didn't want it to do the detail,
我不希望它是 detail
I wanted it to actually slide on the stack of the master,
我希望它存在在 master 中的 stack 中
cuz the master could be a stack then I would use show.
因为 master 可以是一个 stack，这种情况我就会用 show
All right?
好吧
I could also make it a popover or a model here.
我也可以让它以 popover 或者 model 的形式展示
So I'm gonna pick show detail, that's what I want.
这里我选择 show detail，这是正是我想要的
And it's gonna make a line appear in the story board.
这将会在 storyboard 中出现一条连线
And the middle of the line is a little round circle.
线的中间有个小小的圆圈
If you click on that and bring up the attribute
如果你点击它，会在 attribute inspector 中显示出它的属性
inspector, on the right you'll see that there's a little pop
在右边你就能看到这个下拉框
up that says what kind of segue you want.
上面显示你用的是哪种 segue
We already, we already chose this one to be show detail.
我们已经选择了这个 segue 为 show detail 这个类型
And there's also a critical field there called Identifier.
这里还有一个重要的区域，叫做 Identifier
That's a unique Identifier for
这是你的这个 segue 唯一的标志
this segue, and you need this Identifier.
你将会在后面用得到这个 Identifier
Let's talk about, why we need this Identifier?
我们来说说为什么需要这个 Identifier
So I'm gonna call this Identifier for
我就把这个 Identifier
this one Show Graph.
叫做 Show Graph
And you should usually, call the segue something that
一般来说你应该把 segue 命名为
is probably a verb phrase that says what this segue does.
也许是一个动词词组，这个名字能够告诉别人这个 segue 是用来做什么的
So this segue when you're pressing the button it
这里的这个 segue 是当你按下那个按钮
shows a graph so I'm gonna call it Show Graph, okay?
它显示出一个图标，所以我就叫它为 Show Graph
So just type that in there.
把名字输入上去就好了
So, I told you before that everything in the storyboard
我曾经曰过，storyboard 的所有东西
is linked up with what's in your code by name.
都是通过名字来和你的代码连接在一起的
Whether it's the class of view controller.
不管是 ViewController 的 class
Class of of UI view.
或者是 UIView 的 class
Name of an outlet.
outlet 的名字
Name of an action.
action 的名字
Name of a segue which is
segue 的名字
basically what the Identifier of a segue is.
这里说的就是 segue 的 Identifier
They're all just names, and
它们通通都只是名字而已
we have to make the names the same in our code.
我们需要让代码中的名字和 storyboard 中的名字一致
So it's a loose coupling to make those two
这是一种松散耦合，能让两个
things work together.
东西连接在一起
So, we'll have to reference this name in our code.
因此我们需要让我们的代码和这个名字关联起来
Okay, so where, where are we gonna use that Identifier?
好的，那我们在哪里用到这个 Identifier 呢
Well, one way we can do it, only the 10% case I said,
其中一种方法，很少用到，可能只有 10% 的情况
is to cause a segue to happen from code.
就是在代码中触发这个 segue
And you do that with
你会用
UIViewController method performSequeWithIdentifier.
UIViewController 的一个方法，叫 performSequeWithIdentifier
And you just specify that Identifier, and
你只要在里面用了这个 Identifier，
it's gonna make that segue happen, okay?
就能触发这个 segue
Simple as that,
很简单
so I am not gonna talk about this,
所以我不会讲这个的，
because you're not gonna be doing this one,
因为你们不会用这个，
probably in this class, maybe in your final project,
也许在这节课不会用，也许你们的最后的项目会用到
you might find a reason to do it.
你也许能找到一个用它的理由
But the number one reason to have the Identifier in there
但是使用 Identifier 最主要的理由
and the main thing that it's used for
也是最主要的用到的地方
is to prepare a segue, because when that segue happens,
是准备一个 segue，因为当这些 segue 被触发
it creates a new MVC, that new MVC was just born.
它会创建一个新的 MVC，这个 MVC 刚来到这个世界
It needs to be prepared to do what it wants to do.
它需要一些准备才能做一些你想它做的事情
So for example,
举例说明
in the calculator case, when I segue to a graphing MVC,
在 calculator 的例子中，当我 segue 到一个画图表的 MVC
it's just a blank graphing MVC.
它只是一个空白的图表 MVC
I have to tell it what to graph.
我需要告诉它画啥
I have to prepare it basically, okay?
我需要为它准备最基本的东西
So, that's the number one thing, preparing.
所以这是最重要的，准备
So how does preparing work?
怎么做这个准备工作呢
Preparing very simple.
准备很简单的
The MVC that contains the instigator of this segue.
MVC 包含着一个 segue 的发起者
Like the button, or whatever's causing it to segue.
比如按钮，或者任何能够触发 segue 的东西
That MVC implements a method called, prepareForSegue.
MVC 实现了一个方法，叫做 prepareForeSegue
And inside, it gets the MVC that was just created, and
在里面，它存着刚刚创建出来的 MVC，
it has to prepare it.
它需要为这个 MVC 做准备
So let's talk about what that code looks like,
接着我们来说说这个 prepareForSegue
prepareForSegue.
里面的代码长什么样子
It takes two arguments, okay?
它有两个参数
The first one is the segue.
第一个就是 segue
That's UIStoryboardSegue instance and
UIStoryboardSegue 的实例
it really has two important things in there.
这个实例里有两个相当重要的东西
One is the Identifier, so
一个是 Identifier
you know which segue you're preparing.
这能让你知道你在准备哪一个 segue
And two is,
第二个是
the MVC that it just created that you're going to segue to,
这个 segue 发生时新建的那个 MVC
which is called the destinationViewController.
名字叫 destinationViewController
It has a second argument there,
第二个参数是
which is sender, that's just the UIButton or
叫做 sender 的，这就是比如说我们这里的 UIButton
whatever that caused the segue to happen.
或者触发这个 segue 的东西
You don't usually need to look at that but sometimes.
一般来说你不需要经常用到这个参数
We'll see later in the quarter when we wanna look at that.
这学期后面一点我们将会用到它的，到那时我们再看看它
But that's all it is,
这就是它的全部了
it's just what object caused the segue to happen.
它就是一个触发 segue 的对象
So we're gonna look at that segue identifier.
我们来看一看这个 segue 的 Identifier
It's just a property, segue.identifier.
它只是一个 segue 的属性，通过 segue.identifier 来访问
It could be nil, because you might not have set it.
它可能是 nil 值，因为你可能没有给它赋值
And so you wanna check if it's nil here, so
所以你需要去检查一下它是不是 nil
here I am doing "if let" to check if that thing is nil.
所以这里我做解包，用 if let 来检查一下它是不是 nil
Then I'm just gonna switch on it, okay?
接着我只需要用 switch 来区分
And I'm gonna look for Show Graph, and
我需要的是 Show Graph
once I know that, I'm preparing to show a graph,
一旦我知道了是哪一个，我就需要准备显示图表了
then I can say, give me the MVC,
我可以告诉它，把 MVC 给我
that graphing calculator MVC that you just made.
这个 MVC 是你刚刚新建的用来画图表的 MVC
Now, the thing is segue.destinationViewController,
现在，这个 MVC 就是 segue.destinationViewController
that property is anyObject.
这个属性是一个 anyObject
Okay, so you have to use as to turn it into
你需要把这个 anyObject 变成
the right class of the MVC you just create.
你刚刚创建的 MVC 的类
Now in the case here,
在这个例子中
I created a calculator graph view controller,
我创建了一个计算器画图的 View Controller
I've abbreviated here calcGraphViewController,
我缩写成 calcGraphViewController
although you shouldn't do that in your homework, okay?
尽管如此，你不该在你的作业中这么写
It's just that it wouldn't fit on the slide here,
我这么写是因为如果不缩写就太长了，ppt单行容纳不下
so CalculatorGraphViewControllers are on,
所以 CalculatorGraphViewControllers 是
turning that destinationViewController
把 destinationView 变成
into a CalculatorGraphViewController, and
一个 CalculatorGraphViewController
if I can't do it, well then I can't prepare it.
如果我不能把它变成 CalculatorGraphViewController，那我就不能准备它了
So, I'm just gonna do if let there.
所以我这里用 if let 来解包
So if I can, then I'm just going to call methods and set
如果我能够解包，也就是不是 nil 值，那我就可以在
properties in that calculator graph view controller, that
CalculatorGraphViewController 中调用方法和设定属性的值
are needed to prepare that thing to come onscreen, okay?
这样就可以准备展现在屏幕上的东西了
So again in this case I
再一次在这个例子中
would probably tell it what I wanted it to graph here.
我很可能会告诉它我想要画什么
Okay, maybe I would set it to color, or something else.
也许我会设定它的颜色之类的
The scale, or I don't know whatever we wanted to set here
或者缩放大小，或者一些其他的东西
we can do, okay?
我们都能这么做
Now, I don't put a lot of red on my slides.
一般来说，我不会在我的幻灯片中放红色的东西
And when I do, you really should pay attention, okay?
如果我放了，那你就真的要认真看一看了
Very important thing to understand,
需要理解的很重要很重要的东西
is when you are preparing that newly created MVC,
就是当你在准备新创建的 MVC 的时候
it's outlets have not been set.
它的 outlet 还没被设定
Remember outlets are these
记得这些 outlet 是
implicitly unwrapped optionals, we are always kind
隐性解包的 optional，一般来说
of expecting them to have been set.
它们都是被设定值的
Well, this is one case where that's not true.
但是这个情况例外
When you're preparing your MVC, it's outlets are not yet
当你正在准备你的 MVC 的时候，它的 outlet 还没
set, okay?
被设定
That can cause crashers, that can cause you to unexpected
这会让你的程序崩了，也可能会产生一些意想不到的
behavior, because you set something in preparing it and
行为，因为你在准备的时候设定了一些东西
you're expecting something in the view to have been set, but
你希望设定的东西是已经设定过的了，但是
it didn't happen because the outlet is just not set yet.
它没发生，因为这些 outlet 还么被赋值
So you have to take whatever the preparation is and hold
所以你需要把你的关于这些 oulet 的准备工作暂时存到一个地方
onto it, and then later on when the outlet does get set,
当这些 outlet 被赋值了以后
maybe in the property observer of that outlet, you can load
也许在 outlet 中的 property observer，你可以把
up the information that you're prepared with here, okay?
刚刚准备的那些信息读取然后再设定
I'll see that in the demo.
一会展示给你们看
I've made my demo
我已经故意让我的展示
intentionally crash because of this.
因为这个而崩溃了
And we'll go back and look at why that happens, okay?
我们会看看为什么会这样
But this is red, pay attention, you know,
这个是红色的，请注意，你知道
if your segue doesn't work the first time,
如果你的 segue 一开始没正常工作
it might well be because you're expecting outlets to
有可能是因为你以为 outlet 在
be set when your MVC is being prepared, okay?
准备的时候已经赋值了
So that's preparing for a segue.
这就是准备 segue
You can also prevent a segue from happening.
你也可以防止一个 segue 的触发
If there's some reason it doesn't make sense for
如果有些原因让 segue 的发生不合理
that segue to happen, you could just disable the button,
你直接可以禁用那个按钮
but if you didn't wanna disable the button you could
不过如果你不想禁用按钮的话，你希望能够
click the button.
点击那个按钮
And what'll happen here is your UIViewController will be
这时候你的 UIViewController 会被问到
asked, should I perform this segue with Identifier?
我应该执行这个 Identifier 的 segue 吗
It'll pass you the Identifier and the sender.
它会把 Identifier 和 sender 传给你
And you can just return, false.
然后你可以返回 false
And then it won't do that segue.
那么它就不会执行 segue 了
It won't crash or anything.
这样做所有东西都不会崩
It just, you know, touch the button, it does nothing.
它只是，当你按这个按钮，它什么都不会触发
'Kay, so you can control your segues kind of
所以你可以某种意义上
programmatically as well like that.Okay?
用代码来控制你的 segue 了
So, demo time here.
那么，演示时间开始
We're gonna demonstrate all of this.
我们将要演示刚刚说的那些
And I'm gonna do this demonstration by creating
为了演示这些，我将会创建一个
completely new application called Psychologist.
完全新的应用，叫 Psychologist
Okay, so, let's go over here.
那么我们开始吧
So I'm going to Xcode.
我将要打开 Xcode
And here's Happiness and Calculator.
这里是 Happiness 和 Calculator 项目
But I'm gonna create a new project here.
但是我将要创建一个新的项目
I'm gonna call it psychologist, Psychologist.
我将其命名为 Psychologist
Okay this gonna put it in the same place that
我把它放在和我们前两个项目
my Calculator and Happiness apps were.
Calculator 和 Happiness 相同的目录下
Here it is.
创建好了
I'm gonna move these things out of the way,
我将把这些东西放到 Supporting Files，
like we always do.
就像我们之前做的那样
The images, the assets, the launch screen so that I
这些 images 啊， assets 啊， LaunchScreen 啊都放进去
just have my main storyboard here and this view controller.
那么外面只剩下 MainStoryboard 和这个 ViewController 了
And I'm actually gonna rename this view controller.
事实上我会改一下这个 ViewController 的名字
I don't like the name generic ViewController.
我不喜欢用这个普通的 ViewController 这个名字
I even had you change it
我甚至会要求你们也要改
in the latest homework assignment, because I
在这一次作业中要你们改，因为我
just don't think that's a very descriptive name.
觉得这不是一个带有描述性的名字
So, I'm gonna change the name of
于是我把我的 ViewController
my ViewController here to be PsychologistViewController.
的名字改成 PsychologistViewController
So I have to do that in three different places again,
所以我需要改三个地方
so here I'm gonna say Psychologist. Okay?
这里加上 Psychologist
Here I'm gonna change the name of the file,
这里我更改文件的名字
to be Psychologist.
加上 Psychologist
That's surprisingly hard to type by the way.
抱怨一下，这挺难打的
And then in the story board,
接着在 Storyboard 中
of course, I need to go to the identity inspector here and
当然，我需要在 identity inspector 这里
change it to be a PsychologistViewController.
修改成 PsychologistViewController
So that's those three steps.
就是这三个地方了
So now I have this PsychologistViewController.
那么现在我有了这个 PsychologistViewController
What's this Psychologist gonna do?
它需要做什么呢
Well, he can ask you a question like Psychologists
他可以像一个心理学家一样问你一个
want to do.
问题
And you're gonna give an answer.
然后你需要提供一个答案
And then he's gonna make a diagnosis.
紧接着他将会对此做出判断
Okay. Based on your answer as to
好了，基于你的回答然后
how happy you are or not.
判断出你快不快乐
And then it's gonna use the HappinessViewController,
然后它就会用 HappinessViewController
to show how happy you are, show the diagnosis basically.
来告诉你快不快乐，显示出判断结果
Okay, so we are gonna use both the
所以我们将会同时
PsychologistViewController, and
用到 PsychologistViewController
the HappinessViewController from our last app.
和 HappinessViewController，后者是我们上一个 app 中写的
But let's start with this PsychologistViewController
那么，让我们开始实现这个 PsychologistViewController
here, let's build its UI.
先设计它的 UI
He's going to ask a question, so
他会提问题，所以
I'm going to bring out a label for the question.
我拖出一个 label 用来显示问题
He's going to ask the question,
他将会问
what do you see in your dreams?
你在梦中看到了什么
That sounds like
这听起来像
a very psychologisty kind of question.
一个很心理学的问题
And let's make it bigger font.
让字体变大一点
Maybe like, 36 point or something like that.
大概 36 point 上下
We can make it larger here.
让文本框也大一点
Let's center it, make this text centered.
让文本居中
Let's try to put it in a nice place, okay?
我们试着把它放到一个好的位置
Let's use our blue lines to put it somewhere here.
用这些兰线条来对齐
Let's put it like that, so it's nice.
这么放就挺好的
And put it in a good place.
让它呆在一个好的位置
Let's try.
尝试一下
I'm going to show you a little bit of
我每节课都尝试给你们传授一点
Auto Layout every lecture.
关于 Auto Layout 的秘籍
Just show you kind of things you can do.
展示一下你们可以怎么做
So let's try and see if we can.
那我们一起试试看能不能这么做
We put this all on blue lines up here.
我们把它全按照蓝线来放
Right.
好的
So let's see if we can request, or have it
接着来看看我们能否让它用这个
Reset to Suggested Constraints and see if it'll work, okay?
Reset to Suggested Constraints，然后看看行不行
So here I'm, this is for the Selected View.
这里是给选中的 View 的
To select this view.
选中这个view
I'm gonna go reset to Suggested Constraints.
我将要重置到推荐的 Constraints
Now, let's see what happened.
现在看看发生了什么
Now, this doesn't look good.
这并不好
I don't like this,
我不喜欢这个
cuz I really don't want this thing attached to the bottom.
因为我真的不想这个东西和 view 的底部有关系
But the real place, a good place to look for
但是一个能看到我们 constraint 的地方是
the constraints is over here again in Size Inspector.
这里的 Size Inspector
If you look down at the bottom,
如果你看下去
you can see all the constraints that that reset to
你能看到所有的 constraints
Suggested Constraints did.
这些都是刚刚建议生成的
And I'd like this one, and I like that one.
我喜欢这个，也喜欢那个
And I like that one.
还有这个也是
But I don't like that one.
但是我不喜欢那个
So I can just click on it and
所以我可以点击它
hit delete, and get rid of that.
然后按 delete 键，就把它删了
Now as soon as I did that,
当我删掉它以后
of course I got the yellow cuz it's misplaced.
我就会得到了这些黄色的线因为它没有足够的 constraint 了
So I'm gonna go back and
所以我需要回到这里
do what we did all the way, way back in lecture one,
然后做我们在第一课里面做过的动作
which I'm gonna update this frame, fix the misplacement.
更新这个 frame，修正这个位置的问题
No issues.
没问题了
Boom. I've got this where I want it.
咔的一下，我得到了我向要得结果
Okay, so that's another way to use auto layout there.
所以这是另一个用 autolayout 的方法
Alright, so let's get the answers out.
好的，接着把答案给拖出来
Here's our question.
这里是我们的问题
Let's grab our answers out here.
现在把答案抓出来
So let's, maybe I see a dancing tree, okay?
所以，也许我在这里输入“我看到一棵会跳舞的树”
If I see a dancing tree in my dream,
如果我在梦里看到一棵会跳舞的树
let's make this font bigger again on this one too.
先让我把字体调大一点点
If I see a dancing tree in my dreams I'm probably gonna be
如果我在梦里看到一棵会跳舞的树，我想我应该会
pretty happy I think.
挺开心的
So let's try and put this one where it should be.
尝试把它放在它该在的地方
So I'm gonna try and
所以我尝试把它放在
put this one right in the center of my view.
我的 view 的正中间
So again, let's try and reset the suggested constraints and
再一次，试一下用 Reset to the Suggest Constraint
see if that works.
看这行不行
Okay well that looks bad too.
好吧这个也不太行
So let's go look over and see what it did.
所以我们看看它做了些什么
Alright, well, it aligns center to the super view.
啊好的它在父类 view 中居中了
That looks good.
这看起来不错
But it aligned the X up with this thing up here and
但是它和 X 轴的上面对齐
I don't really want that, so I'm gonna delete that.
我并不想要这样，所以我删掉它
The bottom space, I definitely don't want that.
离底部的距离，我肯定也不想要这个
And it fixed the width.
还有固定了它的宽度
I definitely don't want the width fixed.
我肯定不想要宽度是固定的
I want the width to match whatever the size of
我希望宽度随着里面的内容变化
this thing is.
而变化
So, kinda got most things here.
看起来做了很多东西
But I really don't have a vertical position or
但是我并不想设定这个东西的
horizontal position of this thing set.
垂直位置和水平位置
So I'm gonna use another one down here.
所以我需要用这下面的另一个按钮
This is the alignment one.
这就是 alignment 的这个按钮
And I'm gonna go down here and say, I want the alignment,
然后我在最下面，我希望这个对齐
the horizontal and vertical centers to be lined up.
到水平中心和垂直中心
So I really already got the vertical center right there.
所以我已经在有垂直中心的这个 constraint 了
So I just do horizontal center, so
我只需要再加一个水平中心的就可以了
I'll add that constraint.
那么我就添加了这个 constraint
So now I've got these two things lined up,
所以现在我有这两个 constraint 来对齐
that looks like what I want.
这看起来就是我想要的
Again, it's a little off this placement probably size is
再一次，这有一点点和放置的位置或者大小不一样
not quite right, we'll put that right.
我们把它放到正确地位置
And boom, now we've got this tree in the middle.Okay.
然后我们就让这个树居中了
So let's add some more answers. I'm just going
接下来我们再添加多几个答案，我只要
to copy and paste because I like this fun combination.
复制和粘贴就行了，因为我喜欢这个有趣的组合
Let's say you dream of a dirty Golden, no not dirty,
比如说你梦见了一个肮脏的黄金，不不是肮脏
we'll just say, a Golden Bear.
我们说，一个金色的熊
[NOISE] Okay so let's say the Golden Bear somehow shows up
好吧这头金色的熊无意中出现
in your dreams.
在你的梦里
Doesn't sound very good.
听起来不太好
So there's that.
就这样啦
And this one, let's see if we
这个呢，我们看一下我们
can do suggested constraints with this one.
能不能用推荐的 constraint
Okay, we do that. Now this one looks good.
好的我们点击。哦！这看起来不错
It's got the bottom space and the center.
它有底部距离，还有居中
Looks good, okay?
看起来不错
So we're rocking with that one.
所以我们就搞掂了这个了
No need to do anything.
这个啥都不用做了
Let's do another one.
来加另一个
Buckeye, I'm not even sure what that is, but
加一个“七叶树”，我不太确定这是什么，但是
we'll put that in there.
我们就把它放这里
We'll reset suggested constraints for this one too.
我们也对它做 Reset Suggest Constraints
Make sure that looks good, yes it does, okay,
保证它看起来不错，啊，是的看起来不错
this is just the size inspector right here, alright.
这个是 Size Inspector
Alright, so that's good.
好了，这不错
So let's run our app and see how it looks.
先跑跑我们的程序看看怎么样
Okay, here we go.
好的跑了
Oh, that's doesn't look good.
噢这看起来不太好
What do you see is getting cut off?
你看到这些字被切掉了
Let's see, if we rotate.
我们旋转着看一看
So it's good in landscape.
横屏模式看起来很好
It doesn't look very good in portrait.
但是竖屏就不太好了
So why is that happening right there?
为什么会这样呢
Some of you found this out in your homework.
你们也能自己在作业中找到答案
It's because right now,
因为在这里
we have this thing set to be of a fixed size.
我们把这个的大小定死了
The font size are here, see auto shrink, fixed font size.
字体大小，看这个 Autoshrink， Fixed Font Size（固定字体大小）
And that doesn't need to be fixed,
但这个并不需要固定大小
I'm happy if that's any size.
我会希望
I really don't want it to
我不希望它的字体大小
be any smaller than like 12 point.
比 12 点小
That's getting pretty small in the UI so,
如果比这小整个 UI 就会很小
I'm gonna set the minimum size to 12.
我把最小尺寸设为 12
And now when we run,
现在当我们运行
it'll make the font smaller to fit the size.
会让字体缩小来适应屏幕的尺寸
But if we go to a larger, it will make the font bigger.
但是如果我们屏幕变宽，字体就会跟着变大
Okay. Question back there.
好的后面有问题
>> Is there any way to make it wrap around to the next line?
有没有办法让这段文字自动换行呢
>> So the question is,
所以问题是
is there any way to make this text wrap to the next line?
有没有办法让这些文字自动换行到下一行
And there is.There's a couple of ways to do it.
有的，有几个方法来实现
There's UI text view,
有一个是 UI TextView
which is a very powerful text wrapping one.
这是个非常强大的可以让文字换行的东西
But even Label, you can go here to the Label and
不过即使使用 Label，你可以点击你的 Label
when you inspect it, you can say,
然后去到 inspector，你可以选择
how you want the line breaks to happen.
你想怎么断句
You see here it says truncate tail.
你看这里说的是删减尾部
And you can also control how many lines long you're gonna
你也可以控制你想要这个 label
allow the label to be.
能显示多少行
Okay, so now we have this good UI, and we want to
好的，所以我们有这个做好的 UI，然后我们打算
make it so that it works with the Happiness View Controller.
让它和我们的 Happiness View Controller 一起工作
So we need our Happiness View Controller.
所以我们需要我们的 Happiness View Controller
So how are we going to get our Happiness View Controller?
那我们怎么获得这个 Happiness View Controller 呢
And the answer is,
答案是
we're just going to copy and paste it from our other app.
我们只需要从另一个 app 中复制粘贴过来
So let's go open our other app.
让我们打开另一个 app
Okay, where is it?
唔，在哪儿呢
It's here, Developer Happiness.
啊，在这儿，Developer文件夹，Happiness
I'm just gonna open Happiness in Xcode.
我用 Xcode 打开 Happiness
Here it is.
这就是了
And I'm just gonna first of all copy the code over.
接着我只需要复制所有代码过来
So I have my FaceView and my HappinessViewController.
这里我有 FaceView 和 HappinessViewController
I'm just gonna drag them from one into the other.
我只需要把它们从这里拖到那里
Okay, just drag them from one project into the other.
只用把它们从一个项目拖到另一个项目
When you do, it'll allow you to copy them if you want, or
当你这么做了，它会询问你是复制它们，还是
you could have a reference.
只是做一个引用
If you're going to have a reference, make sure that that
如果你选择了引用，请确认
place you're referencing to stays around,
你放这个引用的位置在哪里
that you're not deleting it and things like that.
放置你不小心删除了它或者对它做了些什么
Or you could have a copy.
或者你只需要复制
I'm going to add a copy, the items right here.
我选复制，选择这里
Okay, so, copy those two things in.
好的，把这俩复制进来
And then what about my storyboard here?
那么我们的 Storyboard 怎么办
I need to kind of get this HappinessViewController
我需要有这个 HappinessView
over here.
这里的
Okay. Over, into this guy.
复制到这里
Okay, well I can copy and paste that too.
我也可以复制粘贴这个
Just select this thing, copy.
只需要选中它，复制
Go over to here and paste.
来到这里，然后粘贴
Okay.
就好了
So, now I have somewhere my two view controllers.
那么现在我有两个我的 ViewController 了
Okay.
好的
Now one thing I notice when you do copy and
现在我注意到一件事情
paste, it doesn't draw the face.
当我复制粘贴以后，脸没有了
It seems like it needs kind of a little bit of a kick,
看起来这需要一些触发，
a little boost before I do that.
一些小的触发动作
So like if you go to FaceView and
比如我去到 FaceView 的文件
just edit this file and hit save.
然后稍稍编辑一下然后保存
It seems like that gives it the kick in the head,
这似乎就可以看到笑脸了
literally, that it needs to draw the head, okay?
确实，它需要把脸画出来
So, now we have it.
那么现在我们是有脸的人了
So, we got our two view controllers here and
所以我们有两个 ViewController 了
we want to put them in a split view.
我想把它们放进 SplitView 里面
So that this is the master, and this is the detail.
这样做让这个是 master，而这个是 detail
So let's do that.
我们来做这个吧
Super simple, we're gonna go down here.
超级简单，我们只需要滚到这里
Go grab a split view controller, okay?
拖一个 SplitViewController 出来
The split view controller's right here.
SplitViewController 在这里
See, here's tab bar controller.
看，这个是 TabBarController
Here's navigation controller, somewhere.
这个是 NavigationController
Page view controller, even.
这个是 PageViewController
We're not gonna talk about that, but
我们不会说这个，但是
that's another way to combine MVCs.
这是另一种组合 MVC 的方法
But let's drag this split view controller out.
我们把 SplitViewController 拖出来
Now see how it
现在我们看看怎么把
comes with other stuff that you don't want?
你不想要的它的一切其他东西删掉
So when you drop it in there, literally just
那么当你把它放在这里，简单地选择
select the stuff you don't want and delete it.
你不想要的东西，然后删除
Okay. Don't want any of that stuff.
好吧。不想要
Trying to be helpful.
那些可能有用而我们不想要的东西
And so here's my split view controller, okay and
那么这就是我的 Split View Controller 了，
here's my master and detail.
然后这个是 master 和 detail
I'm just gonna control drag.
我只需要 control 加拖动
To set my master.
去设置它为 master
So here's the master.
这就是 master 了
And I'm gonna control drag, to set the detail.
接着我 control 加拖动去设置 detail
Okay. That's it.
好了就这样
So let's run.
让我们跑跑
Let's actually run on an iPad.
让我们在 iPad 上跑一下
See what this looks like.
看看这是什么样子
[BLANK AUDIO] Alright, so here's an iPad.
好咧，这是 iPad
Oh, I thought I was gonna get a split view, with this thing.
噢我想我会在这里得到一个 Split View
How come I don't get a split view?
但是为什么我没有 Split View 呢
>> [INAUDIBLE] >> What?
什么
>> [INAUDIBLE] >> Yes, exactly.
对哒
Very good job.
机智如你
You should get extra credit or something up there.
我应该给你一些棒棒糖奖励
Yeah, the problem is this UI comes in through this arrow,
是的，问题在于 UI 启动会从这个箭头开始
so it comes to here.
现在它从这里启动
So it's bypassing the split view.
所以它跳过了这个 Split View
It's not even going.
它甚至没有经过
So it's just a common mistake you'll do,
这是个常见的错误
you'll forget to move this.
你可能会忘记移动这个箭头
And you can just pick this arrow up and
那么你只需要把箭头拖动
move it over here.
移动到这里
Okay.
好的
Now when we run, it's going to come in, via the split view.
现在当我们运行，UI 将从 Split View 开始
And it is a split view.
这里确实有 Split View
If I slide out from the left,
如果我从左边划开
there's my master and here's my detail.
这是我的 master，而这是我的 detail
Okay. And if I rotate.
好的，如果我旋转屏幕
Okay. I get the master and detail on
那么我就有 master 和 detail 同时在
the screen at the same time.
同一个屏幕上了
Sound good? Now clicking this doesn't seem
听起来很棒不是么？现在，点击似乎没有
to do anything, okay.
触发什么
So we're gonna have to fix that.
接下来我们需要实现它们
And let's go look at it on an iPhone see what it
让我们看看程序在 iPhone 上跑
looks like there?
是什么样子的
I didn't hit the button sorry Alright, here's my iPhone.
我忘记点运行按钮了抱歉同学们，好的，这是我的 iPhone
Okay?
好吧
Oh.
噢
Wait.
等等
How do I?
我是怎么
I can't see the face.
我看不到笑脸了
Okay? Let's try landscape.
好吧？试试横着屏幕
That doesn't work either.
还是不行。
So there's no way to get at the face, right now.
看来是怎么都看不到笑脸了。
Absolutely no way to get the face.
貌似完全没办法了，
And why is that?
这是为什么呢？
Well that's because again on phone which is
刚才说过了，当设备处于
a compact size trait device.
横向compact尺寸的时候。
SplitView doesn't put things side by side, it just doesn't do that, okay.
SplitView 是不会左右平铺开的，
Now if we do iPhone6 Plus.
如果我们在iPhone6 Plus上
Try that one.
尝试一下
It's kind of a hybrid.
iPhone6 plus是一种混合的产品，
First of all it's such high resolution that even the small
首先来说，它虽然小，但是确有高分辨率的屏幕，
versions, the smallest I can get it.
是高分辨率设备里最小的。
But see, in portrait,
看，在竖屏的时候，
I have the same problem as another iPhone.
遇到了和其它iPhone一样的问题，
There's just no way for me to get to the face.
看不到笑脸
Cuz it's no way to,
没办法，
if I try sliding out from the side, nothing happens.
即使我从左边滑动，也没用。
Okay? Because in portrait mode,
因为在竖屏下，
the iPhone 6 Plus works like an iPhone.
iPhone6 Plus和其它iPhine没区别。
But in landscape, on iPhone 6 Plus,
但是在iPhone6 plus的横屏下，
it's big enough, that it can actually show them both. Okay?
因为足够大，所以两部分就可以完全显示。
So that's kinda cool.
这个非常酷。
Alright but it still doesn't work. Okay.
但是这个摁钮依然不能用。
So why does this not work?
为什么没用？
Well, it doesn't work because we have no segues.
因为我们还没有加入segue。
We don't describe how to get from one of
还没有告诉程序如何从这个地方跳转到
these things to another.
另一个地方。
So let's put some segues in.
现在我们来加入segue。
What we're gonna do,
在segue之前，
well, actually before we do the segues,
我们要做的是，
let's fix this problem with the iPhone not working.
如何修复在iPhone上的这个问题，
Okay, let's fix the problem where we can't see the iPhone.
修复在iPhone上看不到两个视图的问题，
In order to fix that, what we talked about in the slides,
我们需要把主视图放到一个
by putting this guy in a navigation controller.Okay.
Navigation Controller里来解决这个问题。
So let's go do that.
下面开始做，
We're gonna do that with embed.
进到embed in里边，
In Navigation Controller.
选Navigation Controller。
It puts it in a navigation controller, okay.
现在主视图在Navigation Controller里，
Now when we run on the iPhone, we'll just run it in normal
现在我们在普通的iPhone上运行一下，
iPhone, you'll see that we get the face.
可以正常看到笑脸了。
Okay? Awesome.
厉害吧。
And we can go back to the master and
可以正常的回到主视图，
there's no way to get back to the detail.Okay.
但是没办法回到笑脸了。
So now we definitely need those segues.
所以现在我们必须要用到segue了。
We need these buttons to cause a segue to happen to the detail.
所以我们现在需要通过点击这些摁钮跳转到笑脸。
Okay. So that's what we're gonna do next.
我们接下来做这个，
And actually, let's take a second here and
在这之前，我们先看一下
show what this looks like on the iPad.
加了Navigation Controller之后，
We added the navigation controller here.
在iPad上看起来是什么样的。
Let's see what effect it had on the iPad.
看一下在iPad上会有什么影响。
And the answer is, that the master now has a title.
看，主视图上现在有了一个标题，
See? Has a title there.
看到没？这有个标题。
And this kind of would be nice,
在这放一个标题我
even to put a title in here.
感觉挺好的。
So we can go over here, and actually double click on here,
现在我们可以双击这，
and put in psychologist.
然后输入 psychologist 。
Put a title in there.
设置一个标题。
Notice, look what happened to our question.
注意看我们刚才设置的问题。
It kind of got obscured.
被挡住了。
Do you see that?
看到了吗？
By this title.
被标题挡住了。
And actually we have a warning up here.
上边有一个警告，
Do you see that warning?
看见那个警告了么？
That warning is about that.
那个警告说的是。。
Let's click on it.
点一下看看。
It says, the frame for what you see in your dreams will be different at run time.
它说，这个问题的label的frame在运行时看上去会不一样。
That's because it's going to automatically move it down underneath this.
因为在运行时它会自动往下挪到标题下边。
And we can make that happen in our storyboard by going over
在 storyboard 上也可以修改好，
here, clicking here, doing what we always do when we
就像我们平时修复 auto layout的问题一样，
have a problem with our auto layout,
点这里。
fix our misplacement and it will move it back down. Okay.
修复一下，它就往下移了。
Alright so this is looking good.
现在看上去没问题了。
So let's get this segue business happening.
好了，现在开始加segue了。
So I told you the segues are done just with control drag. Okay.
前面说过了，segue 也是通过control ＋ 拖拽实现的。
When we click one of these things I wanna segue to
当点击这些摁钮的时候，我希望看到一个脸
a face that shows the diagnosis based on
作为在梦里见到的东西
what you saw in your dreams.
的诊断结果。
So we do this just with Ctrl+drag.
开始 control ＋ 拖拽，
So let's Ctrl+drag from Golden Bear.
咱们从 Golden Bear 拽到
Down here.
这里。
See how it's grabbing on to this MVC down here?
看到下边这个MVC的变化了吗？
So we'll let go and
松手
it says what kind of segue do you want.
然后Xcode问我们需要什么类型的segue。
And we're going to do show detail because we want it to
我们选 show detail，因为我们希望诊断结果显示在
show it in the detail side of the split view, and
SplitView的细节视图部分，在Navination Controller里
in the navigation control it will just push it.
把它推进来。
But the show detail will do the split view thing.
虽然实际上它在做SplitView的事情。
So, there we go and
下边我们
look what happened there we got this little segue.
看看有了这个segue，会发生什么。
If we inspect it, over here,
如果我们点击它，在右边
you can see there is its identifier.
你会看到一个它的 identifier 。
You can even change what kind of
如果之后有需要，
segue it is in the future if you wanted.
你还能在这修改segue的类型。
But this identifier is the Golden Bear one.
这个 identifier 指的是 Golden Bear。
I'm going to call this the sad identifier, okay.
所以我想让这个 identifier 叫 sad。
So whenever this goes through,
之后无论何时用到这个segue，
this identifier for this segue, is called sad.
它的 identifier 就叫 sad。
And we'll do the same thing here for
下面是 Dancing Tree，是一样的，
Dancing Tree, okay, show detail again.
还是选 show detail。
And dancing trees segue, which is right here.
Dancing Tree 的segue在这，
We're gonna call this one, happy.
我们叫它 happy。
That's the happy one.
这个就叫happy了。
Now, I told you these should be verbs so
我之前说过这个名字最好用
maybe this should be,
动词。
show happy diagnosis, show sad diagnosis.
比如 ”显示 happy 的诊断“，”显示 sad 的诊断“
But for demo it's less typing later,
因为这是演示，我们就少打点字儿。
I'm just putting happy in that.
所以就叫 happy 吧。
How about buckeye.
Buckeye 呢？
Okay, we'll say show detail.
还是 show detail。
And for the buckeye one. Where is that one?
Buckeye的segue 是哪个？
That's this one I guess.
应该是这个。
We'll say meh. Okay, not happy or sad.
我们叫它 meh， 既不开心也不难过。
Okay, and you can move these things around.
你可以随意的拖拽。
Right, if you're having trouble selecting them or
当你不好选上这些的时候，
whatever, you can move them around to get at them better.
你能拖拽调整一下
Okay.
So this is what our storyboard looks like now.
现在我们的 storyboard 看上去是这样的。
Let's make some more space so you can see it, right here.
腾出点空间看的更清楚。
And we've got our detail.
这是我们的细节视图。
Let me whip this up here.
调整一下。
And we got our master and we've got the segues now.
这是主视图，这是segue。
So let's go ahead and run, and see if this works.
运行一下看看效果
Let's go.
走你。
On iPad, okay, huh, does not appear to work on the i-Pad,
在iPad上运行，啊，貌似在iPad上不行，
huh, that's interesting.
奇怪。
Alright, let's try it on the iPhone.
到iPhone上试试。
All right, so there's iPhone.
iPhone来了。
So we're at the face, let's go back to the master.
我们先看到笑脸，点回到主视图。
Here's the master,
主视图。
notice we have this nice title up here now, Psychologist.
看到我们这有一个标题， Psychologist 。
Let's do this.
点一下，
Oh, it's doing something, but,
啊，有变化了，
it's not actually showing the diagnosis.
但是并没有显示出诊断结果。
But at least it's segueing to the other one.
但是至少跳转了。
Okay?
So the iPad was working too, it's just there was nothing to
所以说在iPad上也是没问题的，因为细节视图已经在
see, because there was already a detail there and
右边了，所以看不到变化。它只是生成了一个
it replaced that detail with a new one.
新的细节视图。
But we didn't prepare that thing, so it doesn't know how
我们没有准备segue，所以它们还不知道笑脸要变化成
much to smile, it doesn't know how to show the diagnosis,
什么样，不知道如何显示诊断结果，
cuz we have to prepare it.
我们要准备了它才能知道。
Okay, so preparing is the next step.
所以，下一步是准备。
We do the preparation for these segues in this ViewController.
我们需要在这个 View controller里准备这几个segue。
This is the ViewController that's instigating the segue,
因为跳转是从这开始的，
so here's where we have to put our preparation.
所以我们要在这做准备。
This is the PsychologistViewController.
就是这个 PsychologistViewController 。
Okay, so we're gonna go over here to
所以我们现在到
our PsychologistViewController code, delete that stuff.
PsychologistViewController 的代码部分，删掉这些东西。
Okay, here's PsychologistViewController.
好了。
And all we have to do here is implement that one prepare method, okay.
我们要做的就是在这实现一个准备的方法，
So it's called prepareForSegue.
这个方法叫 prepareForSegue 。
'Kay, I'll let it type it out for me by hitting tab.
我可以先打这个字儿然后摁 tab 。
And you can see there's the two arguments, the segue and the sender.
可以看到这个方法有两个参数，segue 和 sender 。
Now I'm gonna just say here, if the segue's
这我就可以写，if segue 的
destinationViewController, sorry, if I can let HVC,
destinationViewController，啊，对不起， if let HVC ，
HappinessViewController, equal the DestinationViewController
HappinessViewController 等于 segue的 destinationViewController
as a HappinessViewController, then I'm gonna do
as HappinessViewController ， 然后我们就可以判断
something based on what the identifier is.
identifier 然后写代码了。
Now, if this segue, if we have a prepareForSegue and we're
在这个方法里，如果我们要跳转的
segueing to something that's not a HappinessViewController,
目的地不是 HappinessViewController。
then this if let is not gonna happen.
那么这个if let 就不会发生。
So none of what I'm gonna type right here is gonna happen,
所以下边我即将要完成的代码就不会运行，
and that's perfectly fine.
完全没有问题。
You can kinda do the if let on what kind of
你可以先if let要跳转到什么
thing you're segueing to, or
对象上，或者 segue 的identifier，
on the identifier, one on the outside,
一个在外边，一个在里边，
one on the inside, kind of depends on what's going on.
根据实际情况来。
But in this case, I'm going to do the if let for
在这里，我要在外边先if let我的
my destinationViewController on the outside, and then I'm
destinationViewController， 然后在里面if let segue的
going to do the if let on the identifier on the inside.
identifier。
Okay? So if I had a segue to
如果我有一个跳转到
a happiness controller that had no identifier set,
HappinessViewController。而且没设置 identifier，
then we would do nothing.
那就不用做什么了。
But if it's set, we're going to go in here,
如果设置了，我们就需要一个
we'll switch on it.
switch 。
So let's switch on identifier.
对 identifier 做一个 switch。
If it is the sad identifier, okay,
如果它是 sad，
the sad segue, then let's set our hvc's happiness to 0.
那HVC的开心值我们设置成0
Okay, so here's where I'm preparing, this newly created
所以我在这里准备马上要显示在屏幕上的新
HappinessViewController to be displayed on screen.
生成的 HappinessViewController。
Okay, and if it's the happy segue,
继续，如果segue是happy，
then we'll set the happiness to 100.
就把开心值设为100.
And then, actually for anything else, I'm just gonna set the happiness to 50.
其他的情况，开心值是50就好了。
Okay, something in the middle.
中间值。
Okay, so that's it, that's all I have to do here,
好了，只是全部需要做的，
that's all my ViewController needs to be prepared.
这是我的view controller需要准备的所有东西。
You know, if I had other things in here, I could
当然，如果这里有别的东西，
set other properties, but this is all this one needs.
我可以在这里设置其他的属性，但是在这，现在就已经够了。
Okay?
So it's prepared.
已经准备好了。
So let's go ahead and run this.
我们来运行一下。
This should all work, right?
应该可以运行，
It should be no problems.
应该没什么问题了。
Okay. Here's our psychologist.
好，这是 psychologist 。
Let's try dancing tree.
试试 Dancing Tree 。
Oh, crashed our program.
哦。。。崩溃了。
All right, kind of told you I was going to do this.
之前应该说过我会这么做。
Why did our program crash?
为什么崩溃了呢？
Well it says unexpected,
它说有未知的。。
I'm looking in the console down here.
我正在看下边的控制台。
You should always look in the console when it crashes.
程序崩溃的时候一般都要看这。
Okay? It's the first place you want to look.
这是你最先要看的地方。
This says unexpected found nil while unwrapping an optional.
它说在解包一个可选值的时候意外的发现空值。
Okay, so I accessed some optional that was nil.
说明我使用了一个为空的可选值。
So that's bad.
很糟。
Where did I do that?
在哪发生的呢？
Right here in updateUI, in HappinessViewController,
就在这，HappinessViewController 里的 updateUI 。
HappinessViewController updateUI.
Well, let's see, what in this line might be nil?
让我们看一下，这行里什么东西是空值。
Well, of course, it's the only thing that could be nil,
当然，这是唯一有可能为空的，
which is the faceView is nil.
即使faceView。
What is the faceView?
faceView是什么？
It's this outlet right here.
它是在这的一个 outlet。
Okay, we can also, by the way, go over here and
另外，我们还能在这边
find out how we got here.
看看可以发现什么。
So we got here because someone was setting our
发现了updateUI 在属性观察器里
model into the property observer,
设置我们的model。
we wanted to update UI, and we got there from preparation.
我们希望更新UI，而且我们在这已经准备了。
So here we are preparing,
在这准备好了。
we're trying to prepare this new MVC, and
我们在这准备了新的 MVC，
it sets the model to be something,
设置了我们的model ，
that updates the UI, and we get here and we crash.
然后更新UI， 然后我们在这就崩溃了。
And why is faceView nil right there?
那么为什么faceView在这是空？
Because as I said in red,
因为前面的slide我用红字提醒了，
when you're preparing the outlets have not been set.
当你准备segue的时候，outlet还没有设置。
So this faceView outlet, down here, has not been set.
所以这个faceView的 outlet，还没有被设置。
So, you know, it's an implicit unwrapped optional, but
这是一个强制解包的可选值，但是
it's still an optional, and it has not been set yet.
它依然是一个可选值，只是还没被设置。
Okay, so how are we going to get around this?
那么我们怎么解决这个问题呢？
Well, luckily in our case, whenever we set, if we set our
幸运的是，每当我们设置model的值时，
model and we try to update the UI and the faceView's not
我们就会尝试更新UI，如果这个时候faceView的outlet没有
even connected yet, well, we can just ignore it then,
连接，我们只需要忽略就好了。
because obviously the faceView is up to date because it's
因为很明显faceView是实时更新的，即使它在一开始
not even hooked up.
没有连接。
So we can just use optional chaining here and
所以我们可以使用可选值链条，
just put a question mark there.
在这加一个问号。
Right, and what that says, if this thing is nil,
这个意思就是，如果它是空值，
than just ignore the rest of this statement.
就忽略后边的部分。
Okay.
So, one thing you'll probably end up doing a lot of times
所以你之后应该经常做的一件事就是，
is, in the things that could be called from a prepare,
如果某个属性在准备的时候被调用，
you might be putting this optional chaining in.
你就需要把它们放到可选链里。
Or checking, if base view does not equal nil,
或者先检查它是否为空，
then do something. Okay?
然后在做其他的。
So that should fix that.
这样应该就解决问题了。
Let's go ahead and run this.
运行一下试试。
Here it is.
出来了
Let's go back.
先回去
Dancing tree, very happy.
Dancing Tree，非常开心的笑脸，
Golden bear, very unhappy.
Golden Bear，非常不爽。
Buckeye?
Buckeye？
Okay.
没问题
Working fine, let's go take a look, and
都没问题，然我们试试
let's go look in landscape here.
横屏。
Golden Bear, working fine.
Golden Bear，没问题。
Notice that this MVC underlaps this title bar up here.
注意这个 MVC 在标题条的下层。
You can actually control that in storyboard if you inspect
你可以在 storyboard 里点击这个 MVC，
the MVC, you can click on there,
设置它不要让
say do not go under thing above me.
任何东西覆盖在它的上面。
Also notice that in landscape,
另外要注意在横屏下，
you get a little smaller title bar up here,
标题条变的更小了。
which is kind of nice.
这样挺好看的。
Okay.
But back in here, you get the bigger one,
回到横屏，就大了一些。
because you're getting the carrier and the time up here.
因为上面有运营商和时间等等的东西。
Okay, let's go look at it on the iPad.
我们在iPad上运行一下看看。
Okay, here's this, I can slide this thing out from the right,
我能把主视图从左边滑出来，
Golden Bear, Dancing Tree, Buckeye, working great.
Golden Bear, Dancing Tree, Buckeye,没问题。
We can go over here.
再看看横屏。
Golden Bear, Dancing Tree, Buckeye.
Okay?
So pretty straightforward, the stuff is all pretty easy to
非常直观，所有东西在你的
envisualize in your storyboard,
storyboard 是可视的。
when you're looking at the storyboard it's pretty clear,
当你明白了这些连接的原理以后，
once you understand how these connections happen, to see
看一下 storyboard 你就会知道
what's going on over here.
运行的时候大致会发生什么。
Okay, so one other thing I want to do here is make,
好了，下边我要做的是。。。
let me go back to my simulator.
回到模拟器。
Look at this guy over here.
看这。
This guy doesn't get a title.
这边没有标题。
That's kind of a bummer, that he doesn't get a title right
这有点讨厌，他在那里没有标题
there and he does on the iPhone.
iPhone 那边有（标题）
Right, if you remember on the iPhone, he had a title,
如果你记得 iPhone，他有标题
it was blank, but he had a title.
这里是空，但他有标题
So I wanna give this guy a title on the iPad as well.
所以我想给这个家伙在 iPad 也有一个标题
So I'm gonna do that by just selecting it here and
我只要这样做，选择这里
saying Embed In > Navigation Controller.
选择 Embed In > Navigation Controller
So I put this guy in
然后我就把这个家伙
a Navigation Controller too, down here.
放在 Navigation Controller 上了，在这下面
Okay?
So then, I can have a title.
然后，我就有标题
Now, I could click here to set the title, right here I
现在，我可以点击这里设置标题，就在这里
could say diagnosis or something like that,
我可以使用 diagnosis 或类似的题目
but actually I am going to have the title be set in code.
但实际上我要在代码中设置标题
What I'm going to do is, every time someone says for my model
我将要做的是，每次有人在我的 HappinessViewController
in my HappinessViewController, when I update the UI,
中访问我的 model，当我更新 UI 时
I'm going to say my title equals my happiness.
我将设置我的标题等于我的 happiness
So I'm just gonna put that integer,
所以我只要设置这个数字
which is my happiness, as my title.
我的 happiness，为我的标题
So I'm gonna put that in here let's see if that works.
我要把这个放在这里，让我们看看这样是否可行
So we run, I've got a title.
我们运行下，我有了标题。
Doesn't look I've got there, but
看起来我没有设置成功
no one has set my happiness yet, so that makes sense.
但是还没人设置我的 happiness，所以这说的通
Oh, but it looks like I've
但看起来，这样做我似乎
broken something by doing that.
破坏了一些东西
This doesn't work.
这行不通
Huh.
Why doesn't this work?
为什么这行不通？
Well, the reason this doesn't work is because these segues
原因是，这些 segues
are seguing now to a Navigation Controller.
现在导向 Navigation Controller
They're not seguing directly to a HappinessViewController.
它们并没有直接导向 HappinessViewController
So this prepare that we have right here,
所以我们在这里的 prepare
this very first line is going to not work.
这里的第一行行不通
Because the destinationViewController is
因为 destinationViewController 不再是
no longer a HappinessController,
HappinessController
it's a NavigationController.
它是 NavigationController
Everyone understand that?
每个人都明白这点吗？
So how can we deal with that?
所以我们要怎样处理这个？
Well, that's actually quite easy to deal with.
实际上这很容易处理
I'm gonna create a variable here called destination, which
我将创建一个叫做 destination 的变量
I'm gonna set equal to the destinationViewController as
我将这个变量等于 destinationViewController as?
a UIViewController,
UIViewController
cuz I know it's a UIViewController of some sort.
我知道它是某类 UIViewController
And then I'm gonna say, if I can let navCon equal
我将说，if let navCon = destination
the destination as a UI Navigation Controller,
as? UINavigationController
okay, then I'm going to set the destination to be the nav
我要让 destination = navCon
cons, and what I want is the visible ViewController,
我要的是 visibleViewController
the one on top of the stack.
在 stack 最上面的（Controller）。
Right?
So I'm going to say, .visibleViewController.
所以，我说的是 .visibleViewController
So visibleViewController is just a property in
因此 visibleViewController 只是
UINavigationController that returns to the one
UINavigationController 的一个属性，它返回
that's on top of the stack,
stack 中最上面的（controller）
which is going to be HappinessViewController,
即 HappinessViewController
because it's the only one on the stack.
因为它是 stack 中唯一的（controller）
Okay. And
then here, instead of saying destinationViewController
这里，不是 destinationViewController
here, I'll just say destination.
而是 destination
So now, if we come in here and
现在，如果我们来到这里
this is the HappinessViewController,
这是 HappinessViewController
in other words, I don't have the navigation controller,
换句话说，我没有 navigation controller
then this is not even going to happen.
那这就不会发生
And so it's fine.
所以这是可以的
This will work.
这可行
Otherwise, if it's a navigation controller,
否则，如果它是 navigation controller
I'm going to pull the HappinessViewController out of
我将从中拉出 HappinessViewController
it, and then this'll work again.
然后这就又可行了
So it would have worked in either case.
这在其它情况也可行
So this is nice, in your prepares,
所以这很好，在你的 prepares
to make it so that if you ever think that the thing you're
这样做，以便你认为你将导向的控制器
segueing to might be wrapped in a navigation controller,
可能包裹在 navigation controller 中
this will make it so it'll work either way.
这会处理之，因此它在任何方式中都可行
So later, if you decide to unwrap it or
一会，如果你决定不包裹它或者
whatever, this'll work.
做其它任何操作，这依然可行。
So let's try this.
让我们试试这个
All right, so
完全正确
we've got this Golden Bear, there's the title and
所以我选择这个 Golden Bear，这是标题
it's working, 100, Buckeye, that's working too.
它可以了，100，Buckeye，这也可以。
Okay?
Make sense there?
有道理吧？
All right, the last thing I want to show here is
我在这里要讲的最后一件事是
briefly how to do a segue in code.
在代码中如何处理 segue
Because this segue we did with control dragging in
因为这个 segue，我们都在 storyboard
the storyboard entirely.
中使用 control 拖拽实现的
So how would we do a segue in code?
那么我们要怎样在代码处理 segue
So let's do a different segue here,
让我们弄个不一样的 segue
I'm gonna add another thing to this.
我要做另一件事
Let's go down here and add a new button right here.
让我们到下面，在这里添加一个新的 button
Put it in here, I'm going to call this Nothing.
把它放在这里，我把这个叫做 Nothing
So what do I see in my dreams?
因此在我的梦中我看到了什么？
Nothing.
nothing
I don't see anything.
我什么也没看到
Okay and I am going to put that here.
我要把它放在这里
I'm going to try Reset to Suggested Constraints.
我选择 Reset to Suggested Constraints
I'm going to check to see what it did.
我要检查看看它做了什么
That looks perfectly fine to me.
对我来说，它看起来非常好
I'm rocking!
我震撼了！
But instead of control dragging from here to make
但不是在这里用 control 拖拽以创建
this segue, I'm just going to create a normal target
segue，我将创建一个普通的目标
action method.
action 方法
Okay.
So this is I'm just gonna make this be a completely normal
所以这就是我完全将这个当作普通的
button that's going to do target action from here.
button，它将从这里做一个目标 action
Okay, so let's make some space over here in our
让我们在我们的 PsychologistViewController
PsychologistViewController.
腾出些空间
I'm gonna Ctrl+drag over to here.
要将 Ctrl+drag 到这里
Okay, it's gonna be an action.
这将是个 action
I'm gonna call it the nothing action.
我把这个命名为 nothing action
I'm gonna have the center be a UI button, and Connect.
我将让中间是一个 UI button，然后连接
So now every time I click on Nothing,
现在每次我点击 Nothing
it's going to do this target action right here.
它将执行这里的目标 action
And what I wanna do inside here is cause a segue
在这个里面我想做的是，产生一个
to happen.
segue
Okay?
So base this segue in code, so how am I gonna do that?
所以在代码中有这个 segue，这样我要怎么做呢？
Well, I still have to create the segue in the storyboard.
我依然要在 storyboard 中创建 segue
Okay, so I'm still going to go back here and
所以我还得回到这里
create the segue, but
然后创建这个 segue
the question is where do I create the segue from?
但问题是，我从哪里创建这个 segue？
Where do I drag from?
我从哪里拖拽？
Since I don't want this to directly cause it,
因为我不想这个直接创建它
and the answer is, I drag from this little thing up here.
答案是，我从这上面的这个小图标开始拖拽
Do you see this little yellow guy?
你们看到这个小小的黄色图标吗？
This yellow thing represents the ViewController.
这个黄色的东西代表这个 ViewController
So, when you're setting up a segue that's gonna be
当你创建一个 segue 时，
fired off in code,
它会在代码中生成
you do the control drag from this little yellow thing.
我从这个黄色的东西开始拖拽
So, let's go down here.
让我们来到下面这里
Okay?
I'm gonna take this guy and I'm gonna control drag over to
我将带着这个，我要拖拽到
here, to this navigation controller.
这里，到这个 navigation controller
Sorry for the screen resolution there.
我为这个屏幕分辨率感到抱歉
It's still gonna be a show detail segue.
它依然是个 show detail segue
I'm going to now zoom out.
现在我要缩小
Okay, let's find this thing.
让我们找到这个
It's not that one, it's not that one, it's this one.
它不是那个，不是那个，是这个
And so notice that when I select this one,
注意了，当我选择这个时
it's showing the whole view controller sending this, and
可以看到，整个 view controller 发送这个
so we will call this the nothing segue.
我们把这个叫做 nothing segue
Okay, so now we have this segue named nothing,
现在我们有了这个叫做 nothing 的 segue
it's not hooked up to any button or anything like that.
它没有和任何 button 关联，或和其他按钮关联
Okay, but if I go over to my PsychologistViewController,
但如果我来到我的 PsychologistViewController
now in nothing I can say, let's make this nice and wide,
现在在 nothing 里，让我们把这个变好变宽
performSegueWithIdentifier the nothing segue.
performSegueWithIdentifier ("nothing",
And the sender, we could make it be the button or
sender : sender)，我们可以让它为 button 或
we could make this actually be self, so
实际上我们可以用 self
that the view control itself could be the sender.
因此 view controller 本身可以作为 sender
Or we could make it be nil.
或者我们可以让它为 nil
Okay?
But this sender, whatever we put here is just going to get
但这个 sender，当我们有机会 prepare 时，
passed along when we get a chance to prepare.
我们放在这里的任何东西都将被传递
Because this segue, even though we are executing it
因为这个 segue，即使我们在代码中
from code, is still going to get a chance to prepare.
执行它，它依然有机会 prepare
So if we went down here and said case nothing,
如果我们来到下面这里，case nothing
maybe the happiness there is not very happy,
那里的 happiness 可能并不高兴
okay, then you can still prepare down here.
然后你依然可以从下面这里 prepare
So even though we are doing it in code,
即使我们在代码中做这个
it's still going to prepare.
它依然会 prepare
All right, so let's go take a look at that.
让我们看看那个
Back to our iPad here.
回到我们的 iPad
So there's happy, sad, and here's nothing.
这里有 happy，sad，这里是 nothing
'Kay?
Make sense?
说的通吧？
So you can do things from code.
所以你可以在代码中做些事情
Now why would you ever wanna do it in code?
但为什么你想在代码中处理这个？
Well, maybe you want to have a button clicked, and then,
你可能想让一个 button 被点击，然后
depending on the state of something,
根据一些东西的状态
it'll do one segue versus doing another segue.
它会处理一个 segue 相对另一个 segue
So you can have a little if then there that performs one
你可以用少些代码，如果要执行两个
of two different segues.
不同 segue 中的一个。
That's a classic reason you might want to
这是个经典理由，为什么你可能想在
do segues in code
代码中使用 segue
versus just control dragging directly from the button.
而不是直接从 button control 拖拽生成
All right?
I believe that's all I wanted to cover today on that, yes.
我相信这是我今天要讲解的有关 （navigation controller）所有内容了
So now we'll go talk about popovers, so
现在让我们谈谈 popovers
let's go back to our slides here.
让我们回到我们的幻灯片
All right, popovers.
popovers
So I don't talk about popovers with the other three, because
我们没有和其他三个一起讲 popovers，因为
it's a little bit different, a popover's a little different.
它有点不一样，popover 是不一样的
So here is a UI that has a popover in it.
这是有一个 popover 的 UI
This is the calendar app.
这是日历 app
And you can see the popover is that whole area there where
你可以看到 popover，就是我在
I'm searching in my calendar trying to find something.
在我的日历中搜索一些东西的整个区域
Okay.
So that whole popover, that little lighter colored area in
因此整个 popover，在右上角的
the upper righthand corner, that is all one MVC.
有点颜色的区域，这是个 MVC
It's the search for appointment MVC, okay?
这个搜索是为了 appointment MVC
So and it completely fills that popover space.
所以它完全占据了 popover 的空间
Now, notice that the popover also has kind of
现在，注意 popover 也有类似的
a little arrow.
小剪头
You see that tiny little arrow?
你们看到这个小小的剪头了吗？
It's just like a little white triangle.
它像一个小的白色三角形
That's pointing to whatever caused this to come up.
它指向让它出现的任何（view）
So in this case,
所以在这个例子中
that little thing that looks like a magnifying glass,
这个小东西像个放大镜
that's what the user must have pressed on in order to
用户必须点击这个，
have this pop-over for searching come up.
然后这个搜索用的 popover 才会出现
Right?
Now notice the rest of the screen here is gray,
注意现在屏幕上的其他地方是灰色的
except for the keyboard, is gray.
除了键盘，都是灰色的
See it's kind of grayed out?
像是灰色的在外面？
And it's also if you tried to click in there,
如果你试图在灰色区域点击
it wouldn't work.
是行不通的
Like if you tried to click on the Week button at the top,
如果你试图点击顶部的 Week button
or the Month button or the Year button it wouldn't work.
或者 Month button，或者 Year button，都不行
But what it would do is dismiss the popover, okay?
它能做的是让 popover 消失
So that grey area, so you can see that it's not as
所以灰色区域，你可以看到，没有和
bad as take over the screen, but it's still the case that I
占据整个屏幕一样糟糕，但依然是这种情况
can only do what the popover is asking me to do.
我只能做 popover 要我做的事情
I can't do anything else until I dismiss the popover but
直到我关闭 popover 我才能做其他事情
it's just really, really easy to see what the rest of
在你把 popover 放在最上面前，很容易看
what was going on before you brought the popover up,
其他都在做什么
and it's usually easy to get rid of the popover.
通常地，很容易就可以关闭 popover
Now, the interesting thing about popover, and
关于 popover 有趣的事情是
the reason I talk about it differently,
我说它不同的原因是
is that it's not a UIViewController.
它不是一个 UIViewController
Okay. Popover is itself,
Popover 就是它自己
not a UIViewController.
不是一个 UIViewController
It's brought on
它是通过一个叫做
screen using what's called a presentation controller.
presentation controller 来出现在屏幕上的
And I'm not really going to talk about presentation
我不是真的要谈 presentation
controller, just a little bit about the popover presentation
controller，只是一点有关 popover presentation
controller, but it's the underlying mechanism that all
controller，但是这是所有这些东西基于的
of this stuff is based on, so popover doesn't really need to
底层机制，因此 popover 并不真的需要
have a view controller whose view is this MVC.
一个 view controller，它的 view 是这个 MVC
It can do it
它能由
purely with the presentation controller mechanism.
presentation controller 机制纯粹做到这一点
So let's talk about the popover then,
让我们谈谈 popover
and how we make it work, because the interesting of
还有我们是怎样让它工作的，由于强大的 popover
Power Popover that even though it's not its own MVC,
的有趣，即使它不是自己的 MVC
it still segues and all that stuff exactly the same.
它依然可以 segue，还有所有和此相关的
You still Ctrl+drag to some view controller.
你依然可以 Ctrl＋拖拽 到一些 view controller
You still get to do prepareForSegue.
你依然可以处理 prepareForSegue.
It all looks exactly the same because it's still doing
你看起来完全一样，因为它依然可以
segues even though it's not its own view controller.
segue，即使它不是自己的 view controller
It's still using segues to cause it to appear.
它依然使用 segue，让它出现
So, things to note when you're preparing for a segue here.
需要注意的是，当你在这为一个 segue 做 prepare 时，
One is that inside your preparer you
一个是在你的 preparer 中，你
can get ahold of what's called the presentation controller.
可以获取到 presentation controller.
And the presentation controller for
这个创建 popover 的 presentation controller
a popover will tell you things like what's the button that
将告诉你一些事情，比如是哪个 button
brought this popover up.
带出了这个 popover
And you can even configure the presentation like I don't want
你甚至可以配置这个 presentation，比如我不想
this popover to pop up to the left of anything.
让这个 popover 出现在左边
I always want it on the right side of something.
我想让它总在右边
So you can even control that.
你甚至可以控制这个
And very interestingly using the presentation controller's
使用 presentation controller 的代理非常有趣
delegate, this is the first time we
这是我们在这个课程上第一次
have talked about a delegate in iOS in this class,
谈论 iOS 中的代理
although we'll gonna talk about it in spades next week.
虽然我们会在下周的 spades 中讲这个
Using the presentation controller's delegate,
使用 presentation controller 的代理
you can affect how the popover adapts to being on an iPhone.
你可以影响 popover 如何在 iPhone 上适配
So a popover on an iPad pops up like you saw in
popover 在 iPad 上出现，如你们在刚才
the previous screen there.
的屏幕上看到的
A little window that pops up.
一个小的窗口出现了
Well on the iPhone it adapts and
在 iPhone 上它适配了
instead does modal, full-screen, okay?
被 model 取代了，全屏的
So it doesn't pop up as a little thing on an iPhone.
所以在 iPhone 上它不是以一个小的窗口出现
And why is that?
为什么这样
Well, the iPhone's smaller and
好吧，iPhone 比较小
so if the thing you're popping up is really big,
所以如果你要弹出的 popover 很大
there might be no way to cram it in there and make it fit.
可能没有办法把它塞进去，让它适合
But if you present full screen modal,
但如果你 present 全屏的 modal
it's definitely going to fit.
它肯定适合
Okay, so it automatically does this.
它自动处理这个
iOS automatically does this adaptation for you,
iOS 自动为你处理这个适配
just like it automatically adapts to split view and
就像他自动适配 split view 和
navigation controller if you build your storyboard right
navigation controller，如果你在 iPhone 正确的
on iPhone, but using the delegate or the presentation
创建 storyboard，但使用代理或 presentation
control, you can actually affect that adaptation.
controller，你实际上可以影响这个适配
Okay. So, here is a brief slide.
这是个简洁的幻灯片
We'll have a brief slide that talks about that in a second.
一会我们有一个简洁的幻灯片来讲这个
But, first I want to show you how in prepareForSegue you
但首先我想向你们展示如何在 prepareForSegue
get a hold of that popover presentation controller and
控制 popover presentation controller
you can do something like set this delegate.
你可以做一些事情，比如设置这个代理
So this prepareForSegue all of the green is basically
这个 prepareForSegue，绿色部分和你在
the same as you would have in any other prepare for segue.
其他任何 prepareForSegue 中做的基本上一样
But the yellow line there is where I am,
但黄色这行就是我所在的，
from the view controller that I'm segue-ing to,
从 view controller 中我将 segue 到
I'm asking for it's popover presentation controller.
我请求它的 popover presentation controller.
'Kay?
So this is an object, the presentation controller,
这是个对象，presentation controller.
that will only come back non-nil, here,
如果我是通过 popover segue
if I'm being segued via popover.
它将只能返回非 nil
If I'm being segued some other way,
如果我是通过其他方式 segue
like just pushing in a navigation controller, or
比如在 navigation controller push
something like that, then this'll come back nil, and
或类似这的其他方式，那么这将返回 nil
I'm just gonna ignore it, cuz I do if let right there.
我将忽略这个，因为我在那里做 if let 判断
But if it is popover, then I make it this popover
但如果它是 popover，那么我将让它等于这个
presentation controller and if you go look in
popoverPresentationController，如果你查看
the documentation for popover presentation controller,
popover presentation controller 的文档
you'll see it has some things you can configure about
你可以看到，你可以配置 presentation 的一些
the presentation like the permitted arrow directions,
东西，比如允许剪头方向
that little white triangle.
那个小的白色三角形
Where is that allowed to point?
允许它指向哪里？
In what direction?
在哪个方向上？
And you can also set yourself,
你也可以设置你自己
the controller, you know you add the controller as
这个 controller，你知道你把 controller 作为
the delegate of the presentation controller.
presentation controller 的代理
Okay, so
好的
when you set yourself as the delegate, what can you do?
当设置自身为代理时，你可以做些什么呢？
What is it going to offer to let you do?
你可以提供些什么呢？
Well, there's  number of things, but
事实上，有很多，
I'm gonna talk about this adaptation behavior.
我会讲下适配特性。
So here's two methods that are in the protocol for
代理可以实现协议中
the delegate there.
的两个 方法 。
One is called adapter presentation,
一个是
presentation style for presentation controller.
adaptivePres...方法（方法名很长）。
Okay, so when the popover is trying to present, it's going
没错，当popover弹出来的时候，
to ask you, how do you want me to adapt if I'm on an iPhone?
会问代理，我在iphone上要怎样适配呢？
Now by default, this is going to say full screen modal, but
默认会以modal方式全屏显示，
you can say you want modal presentation style none
但你可以将展示风格设置为none 。
which means don't adapt.
表示不需要适配
So presented on the iPhone exactly like you do
这样就和ipad上的展示方式
on the iPad.
一样 了 。
Okay, so for
是的，
a small popover, this makes a lot of sense, okay.
对于小的popover这并没问题 。
So this is how you can basically turn off
这是你怎样关闭适配特性
that adaptation behavior.
的方法 。
You can even go way more powerful than that,
还有更强大的方法，
the other one here presentation controller view,
用来展示另一个控制器，
view controller for adapted presentation style,
就是presentationController（）->UIViewController方法，
you can return a whole other MVC on the iPhone.
用来在iphone上你可以返回另一个完整的控制器 。
That displays your MVC in a totally different way
那会以另一种完全不同显示方式
maybe it's wrapped in a navigation controller or
可能被包含在导航控制器中或
it can be completely different.
其他不同的形式 。
So you can really customize it but I just wanted to
你完全可以各种自定义，
show the this first one because it's common to say oh
但我只想展示第一种，因为这种
I just have this small little pop over thing.
小popover很常用 。
I want it to look like a pop over on an iPhone and
我想要在iphone上显示popover
this is how you do that.
你用这种方式。
Okay.
好的 。
The last thing about popover that's important is the size.
poover最后一个重要的部分是尺寸。
So you'd really like the popover to come up and
你想要popover显示的尺寸
be exactly the right size to fit the MVC
正确地适配到控制器中
because your MVC might be different sizes, okay?
因为你的控制器尺寸可能不同，明白吗？
Even as a given MVC might be different sizes and so
甚至当特定控制器有不同尺寸
you really wanna be able to control the size.
而且你希望能控制这个尺寸 。
And in a really object oriented way,
用一种面向对象的方式 ，
the way the system does that, is it asks the MVC that is in
也就是系统所用的方式，会询问控制器
the popover what is your preferred size?
合适的尺寸是多少？
What would you like to be if I could grant your wish,
如果我满足你的愿望，让你来指定尺寸，
what would you like to be, okay?
你希望是多少，明白吗？
So it's cuz only that MVC really knows what
所以只有控制器才知道
its preferred or ideal size might be.
最理想的尺寸
Now that's only a recommendation because
不过这只被作为参考建议，因为
the popover has some constraints as well, right?
popover自身也有一些约束，明白吗？
Because it can only appear in certain places on screen, and
因为它只能出现在屏幕的特定区域，
the screen is only so big, and those arrows might have to go
而屏幕只有这么大，箭头要指向
a certain direction, they might be restricted, so
特定方向，他们或许被 限制了，所以
the popover has got its own things to deal with.
popover也要考虑自身的约束。
But it's going to ask the MVC it's putting inside of
但是它会询问其中的控制器
itself what would you like to be?
应该怎样展示呢？
And so this is just a property in your UI view controller.
这只是控制器的一个属性
You can, for example, override this.
你可以重写它 .
Okay. Override the property and
好的，重写这个属性
return your preferred size.
并返回合适的尺寸 .
Or you can set.
或者你可以直接设置 .
It's a settable property so
这个属性是可写的
you can set your preferred size.
所以你可以设置合适的尺寸 .
If your preferred size is always an exact size just set
如果你的尺寸是固定的
your preferred size to that.
直接设置成它就可以了 。
Or, if you have to calculate your preferred size based on
或者，你必须计算合适的尺寸根据
what your content is, which you're going to
控制器的内容，你
see in the demo that I'm going to show about popovers
一会儿将会看到
in a moment here, than you can override it,
我如何在案例中
which is what I did in that demo.
重写属性。
'Kay, so, we're gonna have
好的，我们会
a demo here which is adding a popover to psychologists.
在案例的时候为psychologists添加popover
Popovers I
popovers会
made them extra credit on your homework assignment.
为你的课后作业增加学分
So you don't have to do them but I recommend doing it cuz
虽然你不需要做这个 但是我还是推荐你做
it's a good experience to make a popover.
因为做popover的体验很有趣 。
Okay, it is something.
好的
If I had enough kind of room in your assignment to
如果我觉得你的作业还有提升的空间
fit popovers, I wouldn't have made it extra credit, but
我不会给你额外的学分，但是
I just feel I have only given you one week's worth of work,
由于这只是一周的作业
I don't want to over burden you,
我不想你们有太多负担
but this is an extra credit you really want to try to do,
但这个额外的学分很值得你尝试，
I think, if you can.
如果你可以的话 。
Because in your final project, you're almost certainly going
因为在期末项目上，你很可能会
to have some reason, hopefully to put a popover in there.
使用到popover 。
Okay now before I do the demo let me talk about
在我做案例之前我想讲一下
what's coming up because I never go back to the slides.
接下来的内容，因为我不会再展示这个课件
Friday we are gonna have that Friday section again for
星期五的部分
IT & T people sorry it's not gonna be on video.
不会录制课程
It's not in a room that we can do the video in really.
因为是在另外一个教室，我们无法录制课程。
So that should be a good one.
那应该是不错的内容。
And that's also an extra credit item in
这也是一个额外学分
your homework is to analyze your performance of your
如果你在课后作业中
calculator that you're doing, your graphing calculator.
分析你的计算器的性能。
And find out where it's slow and
然后找出是哪里导致程序变慢
then maybe you can fix it if you want,
并修复它 ，
that's another extra credit to try and go fix it.
这是另外一个你可以尝试的额外学分 。
Next Monday I'm
下周一我会
going to dive into the View Controller Lifecycle.
开始讲控制器生命周期
I hate to have had put the View Controller Lifecycle onff
我真的很不想把这个内容推后
for so long.
这么晚 。
But in some ways it's kind of nice because it forces you to
不过也有好处，它强迫你
use other parts of your View Controller,
使用控制器的其他部分 来实现，
like the property observers in your outlets, and
比如outlet的属性监听 ，
in your model setting, and things ike that.
就像你设置model那样 。
But you're going to find out on Monday, you're
但是在星期一你会发现，
probably going to be mad at me on Monday when I show you
你可能会生气，当我展示一些
all these nice methods in the View Controller Lifecycle and
控制器中有用的，生命周期相关方法
you're, like oh if you'd just told me that last week it
你可能会觉得，如果你上星期告诉我这些方法
could have made something so much easier.
可以减轻多少工作量啊 。
But the homeworks are designed to not need any of the view
但是课后作业就是这样设计的
controller life cycle methods, you shouldn't need them for
不使用生命周期中的方法，你并不需要他们
anything, even for the extra credits, you shouldn't.
即使额外学分中，你也不应该使用他们 。
And then again, I have Auto Layout question mark,
又一次，我为Auto Layout添加了问号，
kind of a running joke,
只是开个玩笑，
we'll see, hopefully we'll get to Auto Layout eventually in
我们会最终详细讲到Auto Layout的
this quarter, but like I say, see I'm kind of sprinkling it
就像我说的，我在每个案例中都会灌输一点点
in in every demo, a little bit of Auto Layout, so
Auto Layout的知识，
hopefully you're learning a little bit along the way.
希望这一路走来你已经学到了一些。
And then, after Monday, we'll start diving into
然后，星期一之后，我们开始
multithreading, because you're talking about a device,
学习多线程，因为你在和设备交互 ，
a phone, that needs to be highly responsive to the user.
就是iphone，它需要有很高的响应速度 。
Okay? It needs to
明白吗？它需要
always be responding to touches.
响应用户的每次点击 。
It cannot, you press a touch and then it freezes for
不能点一下屏幕后就卡在那里
two seconds or even a second, while it goes off and
几秒钟都
does something.
没有 反应 。
It needs to immediately animating a response to
它必须立即以动画的方式响应
what you're doing.
用户的操作 。
So the only way to make that work if you're doing things
完成耗时操作的唯一方式
like accessing the network, which is really slow,
比如网络请求，这非常慢 ，
compared to the things you're doing on-screen,
相对于屏幕上的操作来说，
you need to be able to do those things offline of
你需要将这些耗时操作移到
the main thread of execution, so we'll talk about that.
主线程之外执行，我们会讲到的 。
Then we'll start talking about scrolling.
然后我们会讲scrolling 。
Because you've got this small screen.
因为屏幕很小 。
It's nice because it fits in your pocket but
虽然这样可以很方便的放在口袋中
if you want to show something big,
但是如果你需要展示很大的东西 ，
you need to be able to scroll around in it.
你需要可以到处拖动它 。
If you want to see a nice image and
如果你想查看高清图片
you want to zoom in and see a really detailed part of it,
而且想放大然后查看细节部分，
you have to be able to zoom in and scroll around.
你就必须可以放大并拖动它 。
And then we're going to talk about the next big thing and
然后我们会讲 另一个大板块的知识
the topic of your next homework after the calculator.
你会在计算器后的下一个作业中用到。
Which is, I know you love the calculator, but
我知道你喜欢计算器，但是
this is your last assignment for the calculator.
这是你计算器部分的最后一次作业了。
We're going to move on to a whole thing called table view.
我们会开始tableview 。
Which is really highly delicate based user interface
它是一个非常精致的用户界面
mechanism in iOS that really helps you understand
它可以帮助你更好地理解
how iOS works when it comes to sophisticated user interface.
ios是如何工作的，当遇到更复杂的界面的时候。
Okay? So that's what we're going to
明白吗？这是我们
be doing next week.
下周的 内容 。
All right?
没问题吧？
Thank you.
好的 。
Okay. So,
好的 ，
let's continue with our psychologist demo, here.
我们继续psychologist案例 。
We're going to add a popover.
我们会增加一个popover 。
And the place I'm gonna add a popover is down here, okay?
我会加在这里 ，
In this HappinessViewController, here,
在HappinessViewController这里 ，
I'm gonna put a little button, here.
我会加一个小按钮在这里 。
And this popover is going to show the history of
然后会用popover展示
all the diagnoses made by the psychologist.
psychologist 所有的diagnoses历史 。
So the psychologist is going to be diagnosing things as we
所以psychologist会记录
click on what we see in our dreams, and
我们的点击历史，
we're going to want a little button here that brings up
我们会用一个小按钮来弹出
a popover right here, and
popover，然后
this popover is going to show the history of the diagnoses.
这个popover会显示diagnoses历史 。
Now since this is a demo, I wanna keep the code simple.
因为只是案例，我想简单一点 。
It's gonna show the history of the diagnosis just as
我只会显示
an Array of ints, because we know that our happiness is
一个整数数组，因为happiness程度用
represented in int.
整数来表示 。
So it's gonna be shown in an Array of ints.
所以会以一组整数来显示。
It might be nicer to show it in a different way, but
或许有更好的方式，但是
we're gonna show it as an Array of ints.
我只显示一个整数数组 。
So let's build this popover segue first and
我们先建popover  segue
then we'll have to go on to build a brand new MVC,
然后建一个全新的控制器 ，
actually, to show the information.
来显示信息 。
It's just gonna be a simple MVC that shows text only, so
只是一个显示文本的
we'll have to do that.
简单控制器 。
And then we're obviously gonna prepare this segue.
然后很显然，我们需要实现prepareForSegue方法。
But first let's build the ui portion of this and to do that
我们需要先完成界面部分
I need to add a little bar but here is so I'm going to
先添加一个小按钮
bring up my object palette here and zoom in on this guy.
打开控件区域然后放大。
And when you put a button here you don't use this UI button.
然后拖一个按钮，但不要用UIButton。
Okay so UI buttons, even if you drag the UI Button here it
虽然你使用UIButton
will look like it is going to work but
看起来没问题
actually don't do that, it will mess you up.
但不要用UIButton，这会有很多问题。
Instead you want to go down here quite a ways
你需要选择最下面的
towards the very bottom and there is this Bar Button Item.
BarButtonItem按钮。
Bar Button Items is a little lighter weight button that
BarButtonItem是轻量化的按钮
goes in bars like this, navigation bars and tool bars.
在导航栏或工具栏中使用他们。
So I should put that one right there.
我把它放在右上角 。
We'll call this one history since it's the diagnostic
我会叫它history
history of what's going on with this patient right here.
因为是diagnostic的历史。
And of course if we're gonna have a popover,
当然，如果我们使用popover，
the popover shows a MVC.
popover里面包含一个控制器 。
So we need to create a new MVC.
所以我们还需要创建一个新控制器。
So let's go back to the top here and get ourselves
所以我们回去创建
brand new view controllers, this is just the regular old
一个新控制器，就是我们
view controller like we've dragged out before, so
通常拖的普通控制器，
I'm just gonna drag that right in here, and make some room.
我拖到这里，腾一些空间出来 。
So here we have this, zoom out a little so
缩小一点 ，
you can see it a little better, and
这样看起来更好，
what we want is for this little button to segue to this
我们想这个小按钮可以segue到这个
MVC, and show it in a little popover right here.
控制器，并显示在popover中。
Okay? So that's all we
明白吗？这是
wanna do there.
所有需要做的 。
So let's just Ctrl+Drag, just like we
我们只要Ctrl+Drag，就像我们
created in the other segue, we're gonna Ctrl+Drag from
创建其他segue一样，直接从
the history button over to this MVC, and when we let history 按钮Ctrl+Drag到这个控制器，然后释放
it's gonna say well, what kind of segue do you want?
接下来会询问你，你想要什么类型到segue？
And we want the propover presentation segue right here.
我们需要popover类型 。
So I'm gonna click that.
所以点这个 。
This is a popover.
这是一个popover segue。
If I click here, on the segue, and go to the attributes
如果我选中这个segue，
inspector here, you can see that it is a popover segue.
然后查看属性区域，你可以看到它是一个popover类型的segue。
I can control where the little arrow, if you remember
我可以控制箭头的方向，回忆课件 里面
the slide about the popover, there was a little kind of
有一个
triangle that was pointing at the thing that brought it up.
小三角形，指向触发popover的控件
Like this History button, or
就像这里的history按钮，或者
in that slide it was a little search button.
课件里面的搜索按钮。
So I can control which direction that arrow pointed.
这样我可以控制箭头的指向。
And I can even see here the anchor.
我甚至可以看到锚点 。
See it highlighting there.
看这个高亮的地方 。
That is going to bring up this popover.
它会弹出一个popover 。
So that's great.
非常好 。
And of course I need an identifier,
当然，我还需要一个identifier ，
just like any other segue, I need an identifier.
就像其他任何segue一样 。
So, this shows the diagnostic history, so
这个segue用来显示diagnostic历史 ，
I'm gonna call this Show Diagnostic History.
我就叫它Show Diagnostic History 。
Oh, my caps lock.
oh 大写键 。
There she is, there.
就是它了 。
History, there we go.
History 完成 。
Show Diagnostic History.
Show Diagnostic History 。
Okay?
明白吗？
So now we've got this set up to this segue and
现在我们已经设置好了segue和
show this MVC.
被显示的控制器 。
Now, this MVC is just a blank MVC right now,
现在控制器是空白的 ，
but let's go ahead and run and see what this looks like.
我们先运行看下效果 。
So this is going to show a blank MVC at this point.
它应该会在这个点弹出一个空白控制器 。
So here's our iPad right here and we'll.
这是我们的ipad，
Go to Landscape Mode.
切换到横屏模式 。
And so if I click on this,
如果我点击这里，
you see I get this nice blank MVC appearing right here.
你可以看到，会弹出一个不错的控制器 。
So our next step in this is we need to create this MVC.
下一步我们需要创建这个控制器 。
All right, we're going to.
好的，我们需要 。
Create the MVC that is going to go in here.
创建一个控制器 。
It's going to be a very, very simple little MVC.
只是一个非常简单的控制器 。
It's just going to have a text view in it here to show text.
它只包含一个显示文本的textView 。
And that's all it's gonna do is show text.
它需要做的只是显示文本 。
It doesn't do anything else.
不需要做其他事情 。
Okay?
明白吗？
So, let's start by creating a new
我们先创建
UI view controller subclass.
UIViewController子类 。
So again I'm gonna go to iOS source cocoa touch class here
所以我会到iOS source cocoa touch class区域
because I'm gonna create a cocoa touch class, and
因为我需要创建cocoa touch class
it is gonna be a UI view controller.
它是一个UIViewController 。
I'm gonna call it text UI view controller because that's what
我叫它textUIViewController
it does, it shows some text.
因为它负责显示文本 。
That's all this view controller knows how to do.
这是这个控制器需要做的 。
I'm gonna put it in the same place all the rest of
我把它和剩下所有的swift文件
my SWF files are.
放 在一起 。
Okay, here it is.
好的，就是这里 。
Here's the code for it.
这是它的代码 。
We're gonna delete all of this stuff in here.
先全部删除 。
Start.
开始 。
Right, so we've got a nice subclass of UIViewController.
好的，我们有了UIViewController子类 。
We'll have to put our implementation in here.
我们需要在这里面实现 。
Meanwhile, let's go back to our storyboard and
除此之外，我们需要在storyboard中
make sure that we set this thing's class in
确保这个类
the Identity Inspector up here.
在Identity Inspector区域
To be the TextViewController, so
与storyboard中的控制器 ，
that we know this is a TextViewController.
关联起来 。
Okay?
明白吗？
Now, let's talk about this thing's UI.
我们先看界面 。
It has a very simple UI.
界面会很简单 。
I'm actually gonna drag out a text displaying object here.
我将会拖一个文本控件到这里 。
And I'm not going to use label.
不要用label 。
Label is nice for one and two and
label适合两到
maybe three lines of static text.
三行的静态文本 。
But I really want something that kind of can show as
而我需要尽可能多的显示
much diagnostic history as I want it.
diagnostic历史 。
So I want something that shows a lot more text.
所以我需要可以显示很多文本的控件 。
A text field is
输入框
not really appropriate because that's editable.
也不合适，因为它是可编辑的 。
One, two, three liner.
一到三行 。
So label and text field are very similar.
所以标签和输入框很相似 。
It's just editable or not.
区别在于能否编辑 。
But there's yet
但在下面还有一个
another one down here, called text view, right here.
叫textView的控件 。
And this displays multiple lines of editable text.
它用来显示多行文本 。
It lets you set the font, and the text can be selectable.
你可以设置字体还可以选中文本 。
You can copy and paste from it, things like that.
还可以复制粘贴等 。
So it's a much more powerful text styler, but
功能非常强大，
we'll talk about this later in the quarter.
后期会详细讲到 。
But for now I'm just going to drag this in right here.
现在我只需要拖到这里 。
You noticed I used the blue lines.
注意我如何使用辅助线 。
I'm going to go up here and
我会到这里
reset to suggested constraints.
选择reset to suggested constraints
I'm going to go over here to the size inspector up here.
然后到size inspector 。
And verify that my constraints are the way I want, and
确认所有约束正确 ，
they look fine.
他们看起来不错。
Okay, so that's good.
还不错
I could also set some attributes maybe, about this
我也可以设置一下这个 text view 的某些属性
text view, like I probably don't want it to be editable.
比如，我不想让它可以被编辑
I don't want the diagnostic history to be actually,
我不希望诊断历史可以被编辑
you know, touched on and edited.
因为点击就可以编辑
But it's not bad to have it selectable,
不过让它可以被选中是没什么问题的
someone might wanna select the diagnostic history and
有人可能会想要选中诊断历史
then copy it and
然后拷贝
paste it somewhere, or something like that.
把它粘贴到别处
Or you could set the font to be larger too,
你也可以把字体设置得大些
maybe something 24 point or something like that.
可以设置成24号字子类的
And of course we've got this kind of
在这里还有一些
pseudo latin placeholder text right here.
占位用的伪拉丁的文字
But that's not gonna matter cuz that's not
但是这也没什么关系
gonna show because we're going to
因为我们会在准备 segue 的时候
set the text we want when we prepare for this segue, okay?
设定这些文字
So now let's go ahead and wire up this UI.
现在，我们来把 UI 元素和代码联系起来
We've got this text view right here.
选中 text view
Let's Ctrl + Drag to create an outlet to it, okay?
按住 Ctrl 拖动，创建一个一个 outlet
I'm gonna call that outlet textview.
把这个 outlet 起名为 textview
So, we've got a nice outlet here.
已经创建好了一个 outlet
And let's add a model to our TextViewController.
在 TextViewController 中添加一个 model
My model, I'm going to call it text.
称之为 text
It's going to be a String.
是一个 String 类型的
We'll start out as an empty String.
先设置成一个空的 String
Okay.
Now every time my model gets set,
每一次 model 被 set 的时候
I want to make sure that I update my text views text.
都要确保 text view 的 text 实时被更新
So text view is this thing that manages text.
text view 就是一个管理 text 的东西
And you can see has an enormous number of things you
你可以看到，一个对 text view 做很多事情
can do on it it's a very powerful text object, but
它是一个非常强大的 text 对象
it also has just a simple method called text.
不过它也有一个很简单的属性叫做 text
Just like UILabel does, and we're gonna set that equal to
就像 UILabel，我们把它
our text the model's text right.
设置成 model 的 text
And just to be safe in case this is being called while
为了安全起见
we're preparing.
防止在准备的时候此方法被调用
Okay, we'll do the same thing with optional chaining in
在这里也使用 optional chaining（可选链）
case our outlet here has not been set.
防止 oulet 在没被设置好的时候，导致程序崩溃
And similarly when our outlet finally does get
相似的，当 oulet 被设置好以后
set by the system, we're going to have it, property observer,
我们就可以获取到，在 property observer 里
say text view dot text equals text.
textview.text = text
Okay. And here we don't have to do
这里我们不需要加问号
the question mark because where actually the text view
因为这里 textview
is being set by the system, so
在 didSet 发生的时候
we know it's set by the time this didSet happens.
已经被系统设置完毕了
Okay, so this is a very,
这是一个我们使用的
very simple MVC that we're using right here.
非常简单地 MVC
And it should have no
它用于显示诊断历史
problem displaying our little diagnostic history, there.
也应该没什么问题
Okay?
So now it's time to prepare this segue.
现在是时候准备这个 segue 了
All right? We want to
我们想要
prepare this segue so that you click on history,
为这个 segue 做些准备，为了在点击 history 的时候
it shows the diagnostic history here now.
展示诊断的记录
We might, we know that this instigator right here is
我们知道这里的这个
inside this HappinessViewController.
在 happinessViewController 的煽动者
So we might think that we should go to our happiness
所以我们也许会想
view controller right here and add the prepare in here.
把准备的代码放到这里
Okay. And we could do that but
我们可以这样做
remember that happiness view control is
还记得吗？ HappinessViewController 是我们从
something we dragged in from another app.
另一个 App 拽进来的
And maybe that's another app that's being worked on at
也许是我们公司另一个 App 中的
our company or that there's another programer who
或是其他程序员
owns this particular class.
拥有的特殊的类
And he said no, no,
他不想让其他人添加
you can't add prepareForSegue to this class.
prepareForSegue 在这个类里
It's a generic happiness showing thing.
它只是一个一般地展示笑脸的东西
It doesn't know anything about diagnostic history.
它对于诊断历史一无所知
And they'd probably be right because if we started
如果我们想把诊断历史相关的东西
adding things about diagnostic history to a happiness view
放进 HappinessViewController 里
controller, it would be kind of a diagnostic or
它就会更像一个
DiagnosedHappinessViewController not
DiagnosedHappinessViewController
a HappinessViewController anymore.
而不是一个 HappinessViewController
So where are we going to put our prepareForSegue then?
所以我们应该把 PrepareForSegue 放在哪里呢？
The answer is that we are going to
答案是
actually create a subclass of
我们会创建一个 HappinessViewController 的子类
HappinessViewController that we can use that's going to get
然后我们就会获得所有
all the behavior of HappinessViewController.
HappinessViewController 中的属性和方法
Plus, we're going to add the ability to do
除此以外，我们还会往类中
the diagnostic history.
添加诊断历史相关功能
Okay. So we're going to
我们开始
create a subclass.
创建子类
We're just going to go up here.
先来到这里
New file.
New file
Again, I'm just going to create a Swift file this time.
这一次我们创建一个 Swift 文件
I'm going to call it DiagnosedHappinessViewController.
把它起名为 DiagnosedHappinessViewController
Okay, because it's just like a happiness controller, but
它和 happiness controller 类似
it's diagnosed happiness.
但是它是 diagnosed happiness
Here it is right here.
这就是这个文件
I'm gonna import UIKit because it's a UI class.
在这里导入 UIKit，因为它是一个 UI 相关的类
And I'm just gonna say that my class
接着，让我的 DiagnosedHappinessViewController
DiagnosedHappinessViewController inherits from
继承自
HappinessViewController, okay?
HappinessViewController
So I am going to be
所以现在
a sub class that DiagnosedHappinessViewController.
DiagnosedHappinessViewController 是一个子类
Make sense?
我说明白了吗？
Now, over here in my storyboard,
在 storyboard 里
I am going to select this scene right here.
选择这里的场景
And I'm going to go to the Identity Inspector, and
选择 Identity Inspector
I am going to say that this scene is no
这个场景的类不再是
longer a HappinessViewController.
HappinessViewController
It is a DiagnosedHappinessViewController.
而是 DiagnosedHappinessViewController
So now I'm this guy here.
现在笑脸的类已经改变了
Now, all my outlets that were set up will
我曾经设置好的 outlet
work absolutely just fine.
如今也不会出现什么问题
Okay? Because I'm gonna inherit all
因为它是子类
the capability of HappinessViewController in my
继承了父类的
DiagnosedHappinessViewController subclass.
所有东西
In fact, what's really cool is I have a scene right here.
更 cool 的事情是
And this scene is a DiagnosedHappinessViewController.
这个 DiagnosedHappinessViewController 的场景
But if I go up here to pick a different class.
我选择一个不同的类
If I go back and
如果我返回
pick my HappinessViewController, and I see it here.
选择 HappinessViewController，看到这里
You can see that it'll show me that that's hooked up.
你可以看到，UI 元素已经连接起来了
Okay, cuz it knows that this is inherited,
它知道这是继承的
this outlet is inherited.
所以 outlet 也被继承了
And so it's hooked up.
也就是连接好了
So I can still go back and show my
所以我也可以
superclasses for my DiagnosedHappinessViewController to
在我的父类
HappinessViewController, and see the outlets.
看到这些 outlet
Okay? So this is an important thing.
这个事情就很重要了
Polymorphism of controllers, here.
controller 的多态性
You often might have a reusable controller.
你也许会有一个可重用的 controller
And you wanna add something to it for
也许你想要在某个 stroryboard 中
a particular storyboard or
为其添加特定的功能
a particular use in the storyboard.
或作为一个特殊的用途
Then you can just create a little subclass of it and
这样，你就可以创建一个它的子类
put your prepare.
在子类中实现 prepareForSegue
So what we're gonna do is put our prepare right in here.
所以我们要在这里实现 prepareForSegue
Okay?
So this
这个
DiagnosedHappinessViewController, first of all it's
DiagnosedHappinessViewController
going to have to keep track of the diagnosed happinesses.
负责追踪诊断记录
Okay. So we're gonna add a new var
所以我们要给子类添加一个新的变量
to this subclass called diagnosed happiness.
叫做 diagnosedHappiness
Or diagnosticHistory, let's call it.
或者叫做 diagnosticHistory
Okay it's the diagnostic history of this thing,
它就是这个东西的诊断历史
and we're just gonna keep it as an Array of Ints.
用它来存储一个 Int 数组
So we've got our nice diagnostic history right
现在我们已经有了诊断历史
there, and now let's go ahead and let's do this.
现在这样
Let's go here and here and
打开侧边栏，去到这里
here to give ourselves some room.
给我们一些空间
And let's override.
开始重写
Actually, we don't even have to type the override here
其实我们不必在这里输入 override
because we start typing prepareForSegue end tab.
因为在输入 prepareForSegue 的时候，按一下 tab 键
It's going to automatically put
它就会自动
the override func in there for us, which is nice.
出现 override func
We don't have to be typing this unnecessarily.
我们就不需要键入这些不必要的东西了
So here's our prepareForSegue.
这就是我们的 prepareForSegue
And so all we're going to be doing in this prepareForSegue
我们在这个函数里需要做的就是
is prepare our TextViewController, all right?
为 TextViewController 做好准备
Because our TextViewController, here,
因为 TextViewController
is what we're seguing to.
是我们将要跳转的
So we're preparing this segue right here.
所以我们在这里做好准备
So we wanna prepare this MVC,
我们想要准备这个 MVC
which is a TextViewController, okay?
这个 TextViewController
So let's prepare that.
所以我们开始做准备
And let's, first of all, make sure that this is
首先，确保
the segue we're talking about, here.
这是我们讨论的 segue
So let's go right here, check our identifiers,
到这里检查一下 identifier
get our identifier out of there.
获取一下 identifier
Let's switch on our identifier.
在这里 switch 这个 identifier
Currently, we only support this one case.
目前我们只支持这一种 case
I'm also going to put this case,
我也会把这种 case
this is something you should probably always do,
你们也应当这样做
which is to put the segue identifier here into some
把 segue 的 identifier
sort of constants struct.
放进某个装常量的结构体中
I'm gonna call this my history struct.
我把这个结构体命名为 History
I'm going to have, and let me make sure this is private.
我要把它设置为 private
Oops. Let's type
打错了
this correctly here, private.
更正一下，private
All right.
Yes.
I'm going to have this be static let
创建一个 static 常量
Segue equal that Show Diagnostic History.
Segue = "Show Diagnostic History"
So this would be a segue identifier.
它现在就是一个 segue identifier 了
Maybe we'd even want to call this identifier,
也许，我更想称之为
segue identifier.
SegueIdentifier
All right.
All right, so putting this in here it just, you know,
这个结构体的作用
collects all your constant Strings together.
就是存放所有的常量 String
And if you ever change something in your storyboard.
如果你想改变 storyboard 里的东西
Some people might even call this struct storyboard, so
有人会给它起名为 Storyboard
that every String that's in your storyboard that has to
也就是，在 storyboard 里出现的 String
match up here in their code, is in one struct.
都要和代码中的这个结构体连接起来
We'll call this one History right here.
在这里我们称之为 History
It's kind of debatable which way to go there.
它类似于一个数据库
So what do
所以
we want to do when that history identifier happens?
在是 history identifier 的这种情况，我们需要做什么
Well, if we can get our segue's destinationViewController
如果我们能够获取到 segue 的 destinationViewController
as a TextViewController,
转型为 TextViewController
that's the only thing we need to segue to with this segue.
这是我们这个 segue 唯一需要跳转的地方
Then we're just going to set the tvc's text equal to
然后我们把 tvc.text = diagnosticHistory
our diagnosticHistory,
which I'm going to do by diagnosticHistory.
这就是我希望通过 diagnosticHistory 做的事情
So, it's just going to show this Array,
我们需要显示这个 Array
this diagnostic history Array, as a String.
把 Array 作为 String 显示出来
All right.
And of course we'll need the default.
当然，我们需要 default 情况
Break out of here.
break 就可以了
Okay? So there we
现在
have this nice diagnostic history.
我们已经有了诊断历史
So let's go ahead and run this and see if this is working.
运行一下程序，看看起没起作用
All right, so again we click here.
点击这里
And, well, it seems to be working,
看来是起作用了
cuz it's showing no diagnostic history.
它没有显示诊断记录
I haven't clicked any of these.
我也没有点击这些按钮
So, since we added this code,
我们已经添加了这部分代码
anyway, I haven't gotten any diagnosis, so that's good.
我也还没有做任何诊断，还不错
So let's dismiss that.
先把它隐藏起来
And here, I'm gonna go there, go there.
到处点一点
Oh, it's not working.
它不起作用了
So why is it not working?
为什么它不工作了呢
Okay, well, we have this nice diagnostic history, but
我们是有这个 diagnosticHistory
we never actually set it.
但我们从来没有 set 过它
Okay, it's always just empty.
它就一直是空的了
And so how are we gonna set it, though?
我们通过什么方法 set 它呢
We are sub class of HappinessViewController.
这个类是 HappinessViewController 的子类
Well, we can just override our var happiness from
我们直接重写 happiness 变量
our super class, and do a didSet of our own in here.
在这里写一个自己的 didSet
So that happiness has its own didSet.
happiness 有它自己的 didSet
And we're gonna add our own didSet here,
添加自己的 didSet
which is we're gonna say the diagnosticHistory plus equals
输入代码 diagnosticHistory += happiness
the happiness, okay?
OK？
You can use plus equals with an Array but
你可以对 Array 进行 += 操作
you have to remember that the argument has to be an Array,
但是你得记住，参数需要是另外一个 Array
so if you just want to add one thing,
如果你想给它添加一个元素
you can just wrap a little Array around it here, okay?
就需要给参数加一个方括号
So here, it's perfectly fine to override a var from your
在这里，重写父类的变量
super class.
是完全没有问题的
If you go look at our super class,
如果你查看一下父类
happiness It has a var and even does it's own didsets.
happiness 变量有它自己的 didSet
So I'm overriding this var, and I do my own didset,
所以我重写了这个变量，执行我自己的 didSet
it does not override or replace this didset.
它没有覆盖父类的 didSet
So it's gonna do this didset, and
它只是先执行了父类的 didSet
then it's gonna do this didset.
然后再执行子类的
So, it'll do both of them.
两个都会执行
So it's a really nice feature, the property observers,
所以这是个很不错的特性，property observer
when you override they don't replace the super class as
当你重写的时候，并没有取代父类的
one, they add on to it.
而是添加了一个
Okay.
So now our diagnostic history is being added.
所以诊断历史已经添加好了
So hopefully now when we go and
希望现在运行程序
look in our diagnostic history, it will work.
能够看到诊断的历史
So here we'll go dancing tree.
现在点击 Dancing Tree
Look up here.
查看一下这里
And look at that!
看！
We've got our diagnostic history.
我们已经拥有了诊断的历史
Let's go over and do golden bear.
再试试 Golden Bear
Oh.
That's kind of interesting.
有点意思
This is not a very good history.
这个诊断历史并不完整
It's only remembering the last thing I redo.
它只记录了我上次点击的记录
I wonder why it only remembers the last thing I redo.
我想知道它为什么只记录了上一次的记录
That's bad.
不对
That's a bug.
这是一个 bug
So, why has that happened?
什么使得这种情况发生了呢
Well, I did it this way to show you, and to remind you,
我之所以这样做，是想要提醒你
that these segues, all of these segues that
这些所有的 segue
are happening here, they are always creating a new MVC.
每次跳转的时候，都会创建一个新的 MVC
So this segue, when we click on golden bear, dancing tree,
所以当我们每一次点击这些按钮
and it segues to this, it creates a brand new MVC.
程序跳转到这里，创建了一个新的 MVC
And since this is a brand new DiagnosedHappinessViewController
这个新的 DiagnosedHappinessViewController
it's going to get a brand new
也会有一个新的
diagnostic history, which is going to be empty.
空的诊断历史
So it is constantly going to
所以每次跳转的时候
be reentering it every time we segue.
都会擦除之前的记录
We really need to
我们需要把这些诊断记录
store this diagnostic history somewhere else.
放在其他的地方
We can't just have it be in a far here.
我们不能单单把它放到这里
And a great place to have permanent storage, of course,
适合存放这些记录的地方是程序的
is in its future defaults.
NSUserDefaultss
Okay.
So let's change this diagnosticHistory.
我们把 diagnosticHistory 改变一下
Instead of being a stored property here,
用计算属性替代
let's change it to be a computed property.
之前的存储属性
So I'm gonna have it be an Int.
它是 Int 类型的
And it's gonna become computed, so
因为它是计算属性
it's gonna have a get.
所以它需要一个 get
And the set.
和 set
And in the get and the set here, and
在 get 和 set 中
I'm gonna go into user defaults.
需要 UserDefaults
Put this diagnostic history into user defaults, and
把诊断历史放入 UserDefaults 中
out of user defaults.
或者从 UserDefaults 中获取
Since I'm going to be using user defaults,
既然我要使用 UserDefaults
I'm just gonna create a little private let called defaults.
我创建一个 private 常量 defaults
Which is just gonna be the
它等于
NSUserDefaults.standardUserDefaults.
You remember this is like a shared version of any of
你们还记得
those UserDefaults that we get.
这个获取到的 UserDefaults 吗
The whole app is gonna be sharing this, and
整个 app 都共享这一个对象
using it to read and write from NSUserDefaults.
靠它读取或写入 NSUserDefaults
Okay. This is nice,
还不错
it's convenient to have this.
有它还是很方便的
Makes the code a little more readable to
有了这个变量，代码更具有可读性
have this be repeated everywhere,
我们没必要每次都重复这些
versus just this little short thing right here.
只需要简单地变量名就可以了
All right. So how am I going to get the
怎么利用 defaults 实现
defaults and set the defaults, well let's do set first.
get 和 set 呢？我们先处理 set
Once we set maybe it will be easier to imagine our get.
一旦完成了 set，get 也比较容易想了
So I am just going to go to defaults,
所以，我只是要去使用 defaults
I am going to set an object and remember that this is
我准备创建一个对象并且记住它是一个任意对象
any object, but it has to be a property list, okay?
但它必须是一个属性列表，明白？
But luckily an Array of ints,
但是幸运的是它是一个 int型的数组
which is what our diagnostic history is.
这就是我们的诊断历史
Sorry, this isn't an Array of ints,
抱歉，这不是一个 int型数组
this diagnose is an Array of ints,
这个诊断是一个 int型的数组
that is a property so luckily, we can do that.
很幸运的是这只是一个属性，我们可以操作它
And here we're in the setting, okay, so
在这里我们在设置中，好的
we're just gonna put our new value here.
所以我们只需要把我们的心得值放到这里
So that's gonna be an Array of ints, the new value.
所以那个新的变量将会成为一个 int型的数组
For key we need a key, so let's go back down to
对于Key来说我们需要一个Key，所以让我们回到
our constants here and add another one, and
我们在这里原来的常量并且添加另外一个
this is going to be our called defaults key, for the history.
这个常量对于历史来说将会被叫做我们默认的key
And we can really put anything we want in here, any name for
并且在这里我们可以把任何想放的东西放到这里
the key, but remember that default is a database that is
key的任何名字，但是记住这是默认的数据库
shared in our entire application, so we might want
在我们的整个应用程序中共享，所以我们也许想要
to kind of name space it a little bit by saying
这个名字多占一点命名空间通过给他起一个类似于
diagnosedHappinessViewControl- ler.History or
diagnosedHappinessViewControl- ler.History 或者
something like that.
一些类似于这样的名字
So this is just a naming convention to throw the name
所以，这只是一个命名约定将
of the ViewContoller or the name of the class in general.
ViewContoller的名字扔进一般类中
That is writing to the default in front.
这是写在 defaults前面的
You don't have to do this.
你不必做成这样
This is purely something you just want to be consistent
这是一件纯粹的事情你只是想要和
with in your whole application and
你的整个程序保持一致并且
how you divide up this name space for the defaults,
你如何瓜分这个 defaults的命名空间
because this is a global name space inside your application.
因为这是一个全局的命名空间在你的应用里
So this will be our History and DefaultsKey.
所以这将会成为我们的历史记录和默认键值
All right, so that's the new write our any time we set this
好的，所以在任何时间那都是新写的
diagnostic history it's gonna write it out to user defaults.
我们创建的这个诊断历史，它将会写在用户的 defaults中
Then similarly we can get it
那么同样的，我们可以得到它
out by just returning defaults.objectForKey.
仅仅通过返回defaults.objectForKey
Same thing.
同样的事情
This History.DefaultsKey.
这个 History.DefaultsKey
But one thing I wanna make sure of is that it's
但是有一件我想要确定的关于这个的事情是
always an Array of int.
它始终是一个int型的数组
So I'm gonna do as Array of int.
所以我将会做和int型数组同样的事
And if that returns nil then I'm gonna turn empty Array.
并且如果那个返回一个空值的话我将要把它转为一个空的数组
Okay. So if I have
Okay，如果我
never saved the diagnostic history to the defaults for
从没有存储诊断记录到例子中的 defaults中
example, then this is going to come back nil,
那么这个将会返回一个空值回来
okay, but I never have saved it before.
okay，但是我从来没有存储过它
So we'll start out with a nice,
所以我们将会在开始时拥有一个漂亮的
empty Array in that case.
空的数组在那种情况下
Okay.
And also, if somehow some junk had got written here that
同样的，如果莫名其毛的一些垃圾写到了这里
wasn't in an Array of Int for
由于一些原因不是Int 型的数组
some reason, then this would also be nil and
那么这也将会是空值并且
we would start out with a fresh Array.
我们将和一个新的数组开始
It would be kind of a weird case, but anyway so you
它也许会是一种怪异的情况，但是无论如何你可以
can see a simple way here to read and write from default.
在这里看到一种简单的方式去从 default中进行读写
Okay make sense, all right so now let's go run around and
好的体会一下，所以现在让我们来回的看一下
see if this fixed our problem, of our defaults not
如果这个修复我们的问题，我们的 defaults没有在附近
lying around, so let's see golden bear, dancing tree,
所以让我们看 golden bear，dancing tree
buckeye, put a whole bunch in there,
buckeye，放了一大堆在那里
history it's remembering them all.
历史记录它把他们全记下来了
Okay.
Golden Bear, 0, Dancing Tree, 100.
Okay?
明白？
That looks quite awesome.
那看起来很惊人
All right.
阿红的
Let's try one other thing here.
让我们在这里尝试另外一件事
Let's go try running this on an iPhone.
让我们在iPhone上运行这个程序
Let's see how this works on an iPhone, with our great new
让我们看看在iPhone上它是怎么工作的，和我们伟大的
feature here, and we'll see what it looks like.
新的特性，我们会看到它的样子
All right so we got there a gold bear.
好吧，没所以我们在这里得到了一只 gold bear
We got a dancing tree.
我们得到了一个 dancing tree
We got the buckeye.
我们得到了 buckeye
Okay, let's see that history.
好的，让我们看看那个 history
Whoa, that looks really, really bad, okay?
哇，那个看起来非常，非常糟糕，不是么？
Well, hm.
好的
So it didn't put up the history in
所以它没有将 history 营造出来
the little popover like that.
像那个小的 popover一样
It took over the whole screen.
它接管了整个屏幕
Modal, it's what a modal segue looks like.
Modal, 这看起来就是一个 modal的 segue
And I put it up here, and
我把它挂载到这里
smashed into my carrier thing up here, and
然后把我的运载的东西砸到这里
there's no way to get out of here there's no done button or
这里没有办法离开这里，这里没有完成按钮或者没有
dismiss or something, because in a popover we don't need to
dismiss 或者一些事，因为在popover里我们不需要
dismiss because you just click on the background.
dismiss因为你只需要点击一下背景
So you know, this is really a small amount of information I
所以你知道，这的确是一个非常少的信息
could have put it in a popover there why did iOS adapt that
我可以把他们放到popover中，这里为什么 iOS适配
popover for the iPhone and put it to your screen?
popover为 iPhone并且把它们放到你的屏幕中
Well, because it doesn't really know how big this is
好的，应为它的确不知道它将会变得多大
going to be and how much data is going to be drawn or
有多少数据将要被绘制或者怎么样绘制
whatever until it's being displayed.
直到它被显示出来
And so on an iPhone to be safe it always adapts
所以在iPhone上为了确保稳定，它通常会适应
popovers to make them full screen presentation like
popovers 使他们作为全屏展示像是
this to take over the screen.
这个接管了整个屏幕一样
Okay, but in this case, we don't actually want that.
好的，但是在这个例子中，我们实际上不想那样
We dont want that adaptation behavior.
我们不想要那个适配行为
We want to prevent this adaptation behavior so
我们想防止这个适配行为
they just keep putting it in its nice little popover.
他们只是不停的把它放进它的可爱的小 popover中
It'll be perfectly fine in iPad and
它在iPad上将会非常完美
it will be perfectly fine for iPhone.
并且它在iPhone上也会非常好
So, how do we prevent this adaptation behavior
所以，我们如何组织这个适配行为
from happening?
发生呢？
To do that, we need to get at that popover presentation
要想实现那样，我们需要得到那个 popover presentation controller
controller I was talking to you about in the slides.
我和你谈论过的关于 slides
And it's pretty easy to get a hold of it.
并且得到它是非常容易的
Inside our prepare-
在我们的准备中
So here's our prepare in our diagnosed,
所以这里是我们在我们的 diagnosed中的准备
DiagnosedHappinessViewController right here.
DiagnosedHappinessViewController 在这里
The same place down here where we're doing the preparation
在这里的同一个地方我们准备那些将要发生的事情
happening, we can also say if we can let,
我们也可以说如果我们可以 let
ppc I'll call it, equal the text view
ppc 我将会调用它，同样的对于 text view
controller's popover presentation controller.
controller的 popover presentation controller
Okay.
好的
So, this is a method in UI viewcontroller and
所以，这里是一个在 UI viewcontroller中的方法并且
it'll return nil if you're not currently in the process of
它将会返回一个 nil如果你不在目前的进程中
being presented in a popover.
呈现一个 popover
So if this segue if we changed this segue to
所以如果这个 segue 如果我们改变这个 segue 去
segue somehow else other than a popover,
一个不是 popover
maybe we wanted to go full modal for some reason or
也许我们因为某些原因想要完整的 modal
we decided to push it on a navigation stack or
我们决定把它推入一个导航栈或者
whatever then this would return nill and
无论怎么样这将返回一个空值
so nothing that I'm gonna do right here would even happen.
这样的话我在这里做的任何事都将不会发生
So what am I going to do?
所以接下来我要做什么？
I'm just going to set the popoverPresentationControll-
我只是要设置 popoverPresentationController的
er's delegate to myself, and that's because the popover
代理给自己，那是因为popover controller的
controller's delegate allows you to
代理允许你
have someone else control the way the presentation works.
使用别的方式来控制当前显示的工作
And this is the first time you're seeing the [COUGH]
并且这是第一次你看到
present the idea of a delegate in an action in an iOS.
在iOS系统的一个动作中呈现出当前的代理
Now you remember when we set ourselves as
现在你记住当我们设置我们自己作为
a delegate you can see there's an error right here it says
一个代理的时候 你可以看到哪里有一个错误
DiagnosedHappinessViewContro- ller does not conform to
它的意思是 DiagnosedHappinessViewController 没有符合
this protocol
这个
UIPopoverPrsentationControlle- rDelegate.
UIPopoverPrsentationControllerDelegate 的协议
And that's true, because up here we have to say we are a
这是真的，因为在这里我们必须说明我们是一个
UIPopoverPresentationControll- erDelegate.
UIPopoverPresentationControllerDelegate
Okay? And now,
明白？现在
once we put this on here, we have to go down here and
一旦我们把这个放在这里，我们必须从这里往下走并且去
actually implement that method, the method we want.
真正地实现那个方法，我们想要的那个方法
And this method that we want is called
并且那个我们想要的方法被称作
adaptive presentation style for presentation controller.
自适应的显示凡是对于 presentation controller
Okay?
明白？
And this is basically saying, here's a popover controller.
在这里基本上可以说，这里是一个 popover controller
[INAUDIBLE] You know how, in a delegate method, we
[听不清] 你知道怎样，在一个代理的方法中
usually pass along the thing that's doing the delegation.
我们通常传递的东西在 delegation中传递一样
So this is that same popover presentation controller being
所以这是相同的对于 popover presentation controller把
passed back to us.
东西传递回来给我们
And it's saying, please return a presentation style which you
并且它说，请返回一种你想要的呈现方式
want and when you're adapting on the iPhone.
当你在这个iPhone上适应了后
So I'm gonna return the UI modal presentation style none,
所以我准备返回 UI modal呈现方式为空
which means don't adapt, Okay do not when you're on
它的意思是不进行适配，不要在iPhone上进行适配
iPhone do no adaptations do what you normally do,
不做任何你通常做的修改
which is put the pop over in a little window.
把 pop over放到一个小的窗口里
And that's it. That's all I
就是这样
need to do to suppress that.
那就是所以我需要压制它的
Now, by the way,
现在，顺便说一下
in addition to PPC delegating inside here, I could, there
除了在 这里的PPT中的代理外，我可以
are other methods in popover presentation controller.
那儿还有其他的方法在 popover presentation controller中
You can go take a look at, and they will show you things that
你可以去看一下并且他们会向你展示出那些
you can find out about what's going on with the popover.
你可以发现的关于与 popover相关的东西
But setting its delegates so that you can control that
但是设置它的 delegates这样的话你可以控制
adaptation is a popular thing to want to do.
你想做的任何适配操作
All right.
好的
So let's go try it now on the iPhone again.
所以让我们在iPhone上再次尝试一次
Here we go let's hit history and
这里让我们敲击 history
now it's working okay coming up in the pop over here.
现在它在这里弹出的 popover中工作的很好
Let's go add history let's go another dancing tree over here
让我们添加 history，让我们在这里添加另一个dancing tree
now we've dancing tree added there.
现在我们已经在这里添加了 dancing tree
Okay?
明白？
And it'll work fine landscape or portrait.
并且它在垂直和水平模式下工作的很好
Okay?
明白？
Questions about that?
有关于这些的问题么？
All right.
好的
The last thing I want to do with the pop over is
最后一件我想对 popover做的事情是
when we ran this pop over,
当我运行这个 popover的时候
over here, you notice that it's kind of big.
在这里，你注意到他是很大的
It's covering the whole smiley face for no reason,
它无缘无故地遮盖了住了整个笑脸
because it really only needs to be big enough to hold that.
因为它的确是需要变得足够大
Well, that's because really again the popover presentation
好吧，那是因为真的 popover presentation
controller really has no idea how big this information is
controller 的确是不知道在这里的信息是有
in here.
多大
And, but there is a way to tell it.
但是，这里有一种方式可以告诉它
And if you think about who knows what the size of
如果你考虑谁知道什么样的尺寸是最好的
this is best, well it's the TextViewController.
那就是 TextViewController
Cuz the text view
因为 text view
controller's the one that's gonna display this.
controller 是将会在这里显示的控件之一
It knows what it's preferred size would be.
它知道它的首选的大小将会是多少
So as we're talking about in the slides.
所以当我们在 slides中讨论的时候
Let's go ahead and make it so
让我们继续制作它
the TextViewController reports its preferred size.
这样的化 TextViewController 会报告它的首选的尺寸
So I'm gonna go over here to the TextViewController.
所以我将到这个 TextViewController中
Okay.
好的
[COUGH] Now the prefered size is just a var in
现在首选的尺寸仅仅是一个 var在
UIV controller so the TextViewController could set that
UIV controller中，所以 TextViewController 可以对它进行设置
somewhere, it could just say preferred content size equals
它可以仅仅说首选的内容大小和什么东西一样
something, but since this is a subclass UIV controller and
但是因为这是一个UIV controller 的子类并且
the content size would change every time this is changing.
内容的大小可能随时发生变化
And also might change depending on
也可能根据一些内容进行改变例如
how big a space the popover is being popped into.
当popover popped进入的时候它占了多大
We can actually do better here by overriding the var
实际上我们可以在这里做的更好通过重写这个 var
preferredContentSize, which is a CGSsize.
preferredContentSize，是一个 CGSsize
I'm going to override it and do the get set.
我准备重写它并且做好 get 和 set.
Okay, so it's going to be a computed property,
好的，所以这将会是一个计算好的属性
get and set.
And on the setting side of this,
这里的 setting的地方
if someone set the preferred content size,
如果某人设置好了首选的内容尺寸
I'm just gonna let my super class.
我只需要让我的 super class
Preferred content size do its thing, okay?
首选的内容尺寸做这件事情，明白？
We'll just let the new value do that.
我们将会让新的变量做那个
So I'm going to let my super class handle it or
所以我准备让我的 super class处理它或者
someone sets it.
有些人设置它
All right?
明白？
But if someone tries to get it, then if my text view has
但是如果有人想要得到它，接下来如果我的 text view
been set, so if this outlet has been set, and if I'm in
已经被设置了，所以如果这个 outlet已经被设置了，并且如果
the middle of being presented on screen, okay, then I can
我在中途把它呈现到了屏幕上，好的，接下来我可以
ask the text view what its preferred size would be.
向text view询问它的首选的尺寸将会是多少
Okay, so we're going to let the textView do the work here.
好的，所以我们准备让 textView在这里工作
So what does that look like?
所以它看起来的怎么样？
So, we might say,
我们也许会说
for example here, if textView does not equal nil.
例如在这里，如果 textView不等于空
Oops, I've got sticky keys on here, so
哦，我在这里按了热键
you see that in the lower corner there.
所以你可以看到那个在右下角
If textView doesn't equal nil, and if we're
如果 textview 不等于空，并且如果我们
being presented right now so how can we find that out?
现在把它呈现出来我们怎么才能找到它呢
UIViewController has another great bar
UIViewController 拥有另一个伟大的 bar
called presentingViewController.
叫做 presentingViewController
The presentingViewController is the view controller that
presentingViewController 是一个视图的 controller
is currently presenting you via some sort of segue.
在当前呈现给你一些 segue的种类
So, in the popover case, it's going to be that diagnosed
所以，在 popover 案例中，它将会被诊断为
view controller's gonna be presenting me.
视图控制器将会把我呈现出来
But whoever it is, I can check to make sure that's not nil.
但是无论它是谁，我可以检查它以确定它不是空值
So, this is only gonna happen right here,
所以，这个仅仅会在这里发生
in the case where I'm in the middle of a presentation.
在例子中我在呈现的中部
Okay, also my text here not to be no it's not clear that I
好的，同样的我在这里的文本不是很清晰
really need to set this because, probably my
所以我很需要设置这个，因为也许我的
outlets are all gonna be set before this gets there.
outlets在这之前就已经都被设置好了
But just to be safe I'll set both of these things and
但是保险起见我将会同时设定他们
in this case I'm gonna let the text view tell me a size that
并且在这个例子中我准备让text view 告诉我一个尺寸
fits inside my presenting view controllers.
可以在我呈现的视图控制器中进行适配
Viewbounds.size.
'Kay?
明白？
And this of course we will need to unwrap.
在这节课中我们需要解开它
But it's okay,
但是这没关系
cuz we checked to make sure it's not nil first.
因为我们去检查确保它在开始的时候不为空
'Kay?
明白？
So this is the bounds.size of our presentingViewController.
所以这是我们 presentingViewController的 bounds.size
So in the diagnosedHappinessViewContro-
所以在 diagnosedHappinessViewController例子中
ller case, it's the whole seam, basically.
它是整个的，从根本上来说
And we're just gonna see what is a good size that fits.
我们只是想看到什么样是好的尺寸和适配
Now this is only a preferred content size.
现在这个只是首选的内容尺寸
So if this size that fits were really huge, for
所以如果这个尺寸适配的事内容是非常大的
example, the popover's still going to limit the size to
例如说，popover 仍然准备去不限制它的
whatever its restrictions are, okay?
大小，明白？
So we just prefer.
所以我们只是提前设定
This is not actual content size, it's just preferred.
这不是实际的内容大小，他只是预先设定的
Now, what if we're not in
现在，如果我们不在
the middle of presenting right here?
这里呈现的视图的中间
Well, then once again I'm going to let my
好吧，然后再一次我去让我的
super class do the work here so whatever it
super class完成这里的工作所以不管
would normally return I'm going to have it return.
它是否能正常的反回我都准备让他有一个返回值
So remember I'm overriding this my super class.
所以记住我准备重写我的 super class
So really I'm just getting involved in
所以我只是卷入
this one case where I happen to be in the middle of
在这个案例中，我碰巧在呈现视图的中间
presenting something, then I pretty much know what my
呈现了一些东西，然后我非常想知道我的
size is based on my text field okay?
基于 textfield的尺寸是多少，明白？
So let's run and see how that fixes it.
所以让我们运行并且看下它是如何适配的
All right, so the goal is to get our history, excellent.
好的，所以目标是去得到我们的 history，非常棒
Now notice also, our history was remembered even
现在可以看到，我们的 history 记住了
after we quit our app and run it again because we are using
即使我们离开了我们的应用并且又重新运行了一下它，因为我们使用了
defaults which these defaults remember things when it quits.
默认的参数，这些参数是我们离开的时候记录下来的
So here we got 0, 150, 100, let's go back over here and
所以这里我们得到了0, 150, 100,让我们重新回到这里并且
do nothing.
什么都不做
25.
Looks good.
看起来很棒
Let's go back and do Golden Bear.
让我们返回并且看一下 Golden Bear
Zero, so it's working beautifully there.
0，所以它在这里工作的很完美
Okay, again it works no matter what size you use.
好的，它再一次工作了不论你设置了什么尺寸
Go on there and it will also work on the iPad as well.
它同样在iPad上工作的很好
There we go.
So, there's the history.
所以，这是 history
Shows it up there.
在那里显示它
There too.
同样在那里
Okay, so that's it for popovers, but we also managed
好的，所以这个它的 popovers，但是我们同样想
to cover a couple other things there along the way.
去盖住其他的两个东西通过同样的方式
Most notably was the polymorphism of
最显著的动态特性对于
view controllers.
view controllers
And we were in our storyboard here,
并且我们现在在我们这里的 storyboard
we ended up actually creating a sub class,
我们结束了实际创建一个 subclass
DiagnosedHappinessViewContro- ller here to add some more
DiagnosedHappinessViewController去添加一些更多的
functionality, okay?
功能，明白？
And that is not an edge case,
并且这不是在一种极端的情况下
that's a common thing you wanna do.
这是一件你想要达成的事的普遍性
You have some reusable HappinessViewController or
你有一些可重复使用的 HappinessViewController或者
something like HappinessViewController.
一些像是 HappinessViewController的东西
You wanna use it, but you need to add something to it and
你想要使用它，但是你需要去添加一些东西给它并且
you don't wanna change it.
你不想改变它
Well, that's exactly what
好的，那实际上就是
object oriented programming is for!
面向对象编程的特点
You can create a subclass of it and
你可以为它创建一个 subclass并且
add the methods that you wanna add to it, to your diagnosed.
添加一些你想要给它添加的方法，对你的 diagnosed
And what's kind of nice too
并且和那样也不错的是
is diagnosed view controller contains all the stuff that
diagnosed视图控制器包含了所有的东西
has to do with the diagnostic business and nothing else.
diagnostic 可以实现的所有事情
So this is a very nice class well contained,
所以这是一个非常好的包含的类
only has the diagnostic stuff in it.
只有 diagnostic的成员在里面
Okay, so that's it, and you don't need this for
好的，所以那就是，你不需要这个为
your homework per se, but there is an extra credit item
你的家庭作业，到那时那里还有一个额外的信用项目
to add a popover so hopefully you'll decide to tackle that.
去添加一个 popover，所以希望你决定去解决它
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
想要了解更多，请访问我们的网站：stanford.edu